1
00:00:47,840 --> 00:00:51,020
aa

2
00:00:49,860 --> 00:00:51,170
There's nothing to tell!

3
00:00:51,170 --> 00:00:53,040
He's just some guy I work with!

4
00:00:53,040 --> 00:00:55,290
C'mon, you're going out with the guy!

5
00:00:55,300 --> 00:00:57,340
There's gotta be something wrong with him!

6
00:00:58,050 --> 00:01:00,910
So does he have a hump? A hump and a hairpiece?

7
00:01:02,390 --> 00:01:04,570
Wait, does he eat chalk?

8
00:01:05,070 --> 00:01:06,420
Just, 'cause, I don't want her to go through

9
00:01:06,420 --> 00:01:08,090
what I went through with Carl

10
00:01:08,470 --> 00:01:11,320
Okay, everybody relax. This is not even a date.

11
00:01:11,320 --> 00:01:12,900
It's just two people going out to dinner

12
00:01:12,900 --> 00:01:14,630
and not having sex.

13
00:01:14,630 --> 00:01:16,540
Sounds like a date to me.

14
00:01:18,990 --> 00:01:20,400
Alright, so I'm back in high school,

15
00:01:20,400 --> 00:01:21,990
I'm standing in the middle of the cafeteria

16
00:01:21,990 --> 00:01:25,610
and I realize I am totally naked.

17
00:01:25,610 --> 00:01:27,280
Oh, yeah. Had that dream.

18
00:01:27,280 --> 00:01:30,530
Then I look down, and I realize there's a phone

19
00:01:32,020 --> 00:01:33,450
there.

20
00:01:34,930 --> 00:01:37,000
- Instead of...?  - That's right.

21
00:01:37,000 --> 00:01:38,420
- Never had that dream. - No.

22
00:01:38,420 --> 00:01:42,500
All of a sudden, the phone starts to ring.

23
00:01:43,020 --> 00:01:45,650
And it turns out it's my mother,

24
00:01:46,500 --> 00:01:49,180
which is very-very weird because-

25
00:01:49,530 --> 00:01:51,700
she never calls me!

26
00:01:56,180 --> 00:01:57,770
Hi.

27
00:01:58,870 --> 00:02:01,910
This guy says hello, I wanna kill myself.

28
00:02:02,350 --> 00:02:03,580
Are you okay, sweetie?

29
00:02:03,580 --> 00:02:05,770
I just feel like someone reached down my throat

30
00:02:05,770 --> 00:02:07,630
grabbed my small intestine,

31
00:02:07,630 --> 00:02:08,820
pulled it out of my mouth

32
00:02:08,830 --> 00:02:10,010
and tied it around my neck...

33
00:02:10,020 --> 00:02:11,450
Cookie?

34
00:02:13,470 --> 00:02:15,360
Carol moved her stuff out today

35
00:02:16,100 --> 00:02:18,240
- Let me get you some coffee.  - Thanks.

36
00:02:22,760 --> 00:02:27,090
No, no don't! Stop cleansing my aura!

37
00:02:27,370 --> 00:02:30,470
No, just leave my aura alone, okay?

38
00:02:31,350 --> 00:02:32,720
I'll be fine, alright?

39
00:02:32,720 --> 00:02:34,920
Really, everyone. I hope  she'll be very happy.

40
00:02:34,920 --> 00:02:35,980
- No you don't. - No I don't,

41
00:02:35,980 --> 00:02:38,510
to hell with her, she left me!

42
00:02:39,310 --> 00:02:41,810
And you never knew she was a lesbian...

43
00:02:45,240 --> 00:02:47,560
No!! Okay?!

44
00:02:47,630 --> 00:02:51,420
Why does everyone keep fixating on that?

45
00:02:51,870 --> 00:02:54,780
She didn't know, how should I know?

46
00:02:56,570 --> 00:02:59,450
Sometimes I wish I was a lesbian...

47
00:03:01,140 --> 00:03:03,490
Did I say that out loud?

48
00:03:04,880 --> 00:03:06,870
Alright Ross, look.

49
00:03:06,870 --> 00:03:09,040
You're feeling a lot of pain right now.

50
00:03:09,040 --> 00:03:11,590
You're angry. You're hurting.

51
00:03:11,600 --> 00:03:13,940
Can I tell you what the answer is?

52
00:03:14,010 --> 00:03:16,090
Strip joint!

53
00:03:17,590 --> 00:03:20,140
C'mon, you're single! Have some hormones!

54
00:03:20,140 --> 00:03:22,330
I don't want to be single, okay?

55
00:03:22,340 --> 00:03:25,330
I just...I just wanna be married again!

56
00:03:29,780 --> 00:03:32,960
And I just want a million dollars!

57
00:03:34,180 --> 00:03:35,370
Rachel?!

58
00:03:35,370 --> 00:03:38,310
Oh,God, Monica, hi! Thank God!

59
00:03:38,310 --> 00:03:39,990
I just went to your building and you weren't there

60
00:03:39,990 --> 00:03:42,530
and then this guy with a big hammer said you might be here

61
00:03:42,530 --> 00:03:44,300
and you are, you are!

62
00:03:44,300 --> 00:03:47,050
- Can I get you some coffee?  - De-Caff

63
00:03:48,270 --> 00:03:50,310
Okay, everybody, this is Rachel,

64
00:03:50,770 --> 00:03:52,570
another Lincoln High survivor.

65
00:03:52,570 --> 00:03:54,080
This is everybody, this is Chandler,

66
00:03:54,080 --> 00:03:55,880
and Phoebe, and Joey,

67
00:03:55,880 --> 00:03:57,800
and you remember my brother Ross?

68
00:03:57,800 --> 00:03:59,760
- Hi, sure! - Hi.

69
00:04:08,650 --> 00:04:09,970
So you wanna tell us now

70
00:04:09,970 --> 00:04:13,080
or are we waiting for four wet bridesmaids?

71
00:04:14,510 --> 00:04:16,510
Oh, God...well,

72
00:04:16,510 --> 00:04:18,990
it started about a half hour before the wedding.

73
00:04:19,390 --> 00:04:22,190
I was in the room where we were keeping all the presents,

74
00:04:22,190 --> 00:04:24,600
and I was looking at this gravy boat.

75
00:04:24,600 --> 00:04:27,730
This really gorgeous Limoges gravy boat.

76
00:04:27,730 --> 00:04:28,750
When all of a sudden

77
00:04:28,750 --> 00:04:29,650
Sweet 'n' Lo?

78
00:04:29,650 --> 00:04:33,410
I realized that I was more turned on

79
00:04:33,410 --> 00:04:35,760
by this gravy boat than by Barry!

80
00:04:35,790 --> 00:04:37,730
And then I got really freaked out,

81
00:04:37,730 --> 00:04:39,070
and that's when it hit me:

82
00:04:39,080 --> 00:04:41,790
how much Barry looks like Mr. Potato Head.

83
00:04:42,120 --> 00:04:44,330
Y'know, I mean, I always knew looked familiar,

84
00:04:44,330 --> 00:04:45,700
but...

85
00:04:48,170 --> 00:04:50,970
Anyway, I just had to get out of there,

86
00:04:50,970 --> 00:04:51,630
and I started wondering

87
00:04:51,630 --> 00:04:55,380
Why am I doing this, and who am I doing this for?

88
00:04:55,550 --> 00:04:57,120
So anyway I just didn't know where to go,

89
00:04:57,120 --> 00:04:59,200
and I know that you and I have kinda drifted apart,

90
00:04:59,200 --> 00:05:01,370
but you're the only person I knew

91
00:05:01,370 --> 00:05:02,990
who lived here in the city.

92
00:05:02,990 --> 00:05:04,910
Who wasn't invited to the wedding.

93
00:05:04,910 --> 00:05:07,530
Ooh, I was kinda hoping that wouldn't be an issue...

94
00:05:22,000 --> 00:05:24,930
Now I'm guessing that he bought her the big pipe organ,

95
00:05:24,930 --> 00:05:26,800
and she's really not happy about it.

96
00:05:28,580 --> 00:05:31,670
Daddy, I just... I can't marry him!

97
00:05:31,670 --> 00:05:35,720
I'm sorry. I just don't love him.

98
00:05:36,810 --> 00:05:39,180
Well, it matters to me!

99
00:05:41,670 --> 00:05:45,320
Ooh, she should not be wearing those pants.

100
00:05:45,880 --> 00:05:47,960
I say push her down the stairs.

101
00:05:47,960 --> 00:05:52,690
Push her down the stairs! Push her down the stairs! Push her down the stairs!

102
00:05:55,110 --> 00:05:57,130
C'mon Daddy, listen to me!

103
00:05:57,450 --> 00:05:58,730
It's like, it's like, all of my life,

104
00:05:58,730 --> 00:06:01,810
everyone has always told me, 'You're a shoe!

105
00:06:01,810 --> 00:06:04,400
You're a shoe, you're a shoe, you're a shoe!'.

106
00:06:04,400 --> 00:06:06,180
And today I just stopped and I said,

107
00:06:06,180 --> 00:06:07,790
'What if I don't wanna be a shoe?

108
00:06:07,790 --> 00:06:12,690
What if I wanna be a- a purse, y'know? Or a- or a hat!

109
00:06:13,740 --> 00:06:15,230
No, I'm not saying I want you to buy me a hat,

110
00:06:15,240 --> 00:06:16,600
I'm saying I am a ha-

111
00:06:16,600 --> 00:06:18,730
It's a metaphor, Daddy!

112
00:06:20,390 --> 00:06:22,750
You can see where he'd have trouble.

113
00:06:25,590 --> 00:06:28,460
Look Daddy, it's my life.

114
00:06:28,640 --> 00:06:32,140
Well maybe I'll just stay here with Monica.

115
00:06:34,490 --> 00:06:37,720
Well, I guess we've established who's staying here with Monica...

116
00:06:38,380 --> 00:06:40,880
Well, maybe that's my decision.

117
00:06:41,780 --> 00:06:44,280
Well, maybe I don't need your money.

118
00:06:44,280 --> 00:06:46,310
Wait!! Wait, I said maybe!!

119
00:06:54,450 --> 00:06:56,400
Just breathe, breathe...that's it.

120
00:06:56,400 --> 00:06:59,460
Just try to think of nice calm things...

121
00:06:59,480 --> 00:07:03,460
Rain drops on roses and rabbits and kittens

122
00:07:03,460 --> 00:07:08,130
bluebells and sleighbells and something with mittens...

123
00:07:08,130 --> 00:07:10,990
La la la something and noodles with string.

124
00:07:10,990 --> 00:07:11,690
These are a few...

125
00:07:11,690 --> 00:07:13,360
I'm all better now.

126
00:07:15,030 --> 00:07:16,520
I helped!

127
00:07:19,030 --> 00:07:21,500
Okay, look, this is probably for the best, y'know?

128
00:07:21,500 --> 00:07:24,300
Independence. Taking control of your life.

129
00:07:24,300 --> 00:07:28,620
And hey, you need anything, you can always come to Joey.

130
00:07:28,620 --> 00:07:31,120
Me and Chandler live across the hall.

131
00:07:31,120 --> 00:07:33,060
And he's away a lot.

132
00:07:34,010 --> 00:07:35,600
Joey, stop hitting on her!

133
00:07:35,600 --> 00:07:37,150
It's her wedding day!

134
00:07:37,150 --> 00:07:39,580
What, like there's a rule or something?

135
00:07:41,320 --> 00:07:44,990
Please don't do that again, it's a horrible sound.

136
00:07:45,090 --> 00:07:46,850
It's, uh, it's Paul.

137
00:07:46,860 --> 00:07:47,790
Buzz him in.

138
00:07:47,790 --> 00:07:50,440
- Who's Paul? - Paul the Wine Guy, Paul?

139
00:07:50,440 --> 00:07:51,000
Maybe.

140
00:07:51,120 --> 00:07:53,240
Wait. Your 'not a real date' tonight

141
00:07:53,240 --> 00:07:55,290
is with Paul the Wine Guy?

142
00:07:55,290 --> 00:07:57,060
- He finally asked you out?  - Yes!

143
00:07:57,060 --> 00:07:59,660
Ooh, this is a Dear Diary moment.

144
00:08:00,370 --> 00:08:02,050
Rach, wait, I can cancel...

145
00:08:02,050 --> 00:08:04,060
Please, no, go, that'd be fine!

146
00:08:04,060 --> 00:08:07,520
Are, are you okay? I mean, do you want me to stay?

147
00:08:08,350 --> 00:08:10,110
That'd be good...

148
00:08:11,090 --> 00:08:13,210 
- Really? - No, go on!

149
00:08:13,210 --> 00:08:15,170
It's Paul the Wine Guy!

150
00:08:18,680 --> 00:08:21,440
Hi, come in! Paul, this is...

151
00:08:22,190 --> 00:08:24,960
...everybody, everybody, this is Paul.

152
00:08:24,970 --> 00:08:25,760
- Hey! Paul! - Hello!

153
00:08:25,760 --> 00:08:27,320
Hi! The Wine Guy!

154
00:08:27,320 --> 00:08:30,250
I'm sorry, I didn't catch your name. Paul, was it?

155
00:08:30,670 --> 00:08:32,980
Okay, sit down. Two seconds.

156
00:08:37,240 --> 00:08:40,770
Ooh, I just pulled out four eyelashes. That can't be good.

157
00:08:42,930 --> 00:08:45,250
So Rachel, what're you, uh... what're you up to tonight?

158
00:08:45,250 --> 00:08:47,540
Well, I was kinda supposed to be

159
00:08:47,540 --> 00:08:51,070
headed for Aruba on my honeymoon, so nothing!

160
00:08:52,810 --> 00:08:55,920
Right, you're not even getting your honeymoon, God..

161
00:08:55,920 --> 00:09:00,830
No, no, although, Aruba, this time of year... talk about your

162
00:09:01,980 --> 00:09:03,900
big lizards...

163
00:09:07,920 --> 00:09:10,620
Anyway, if you don't feel like being alone tonight,

164
00:09:10,620 --> 00:09:12,290
Joey and Chandler are coming over to help me

165
00:09:12,290 --> 00:09:13,780
put together my new furniture.

166
00:09:13,780 --> 00:09:16,660
Yes, and we're very excited about it.

167
00:09:17,340 --> 00:09:18,520
Well actually thanks,

168
00:09:18,520 --> 00:09:20,660
but I think I'm just gonna hang out here tonight.

169
00:09:20,660 --> 00:09:23,230  
- It's been kinda a long day. - Okay, sure.

170
00:09:23,230 --> 00:09:24,910
Hey, Pheebs, you wanna help?

171
00:09:24,910 --> 00:09:27,660
Oh, I wish I could, but I don't want to.

172
00:09:34,890 --> 00:09:39,210
I'm supposed to attach a brackety thing to the side things,

173
00:09:39,210 --> 00:09:42,420
using a bunch of these little worm guys.

174
00:09:43,250 --> 00:09:48,190
I have no brackety thing, I see no whim guys whatsoever

175
00:09:48,190 --> 00:09:51,210
and I cannot feel my legs.

176
00:09:53,150 --> 00:09:54,300
What's this?

177
00:09:54,300 --> 00:09:56,960
I have no idea.

178
00:09:59,220 --> 00:10:01,400
- Done with the bookcase!  - All finished!

179
00:10:05,230 --> 00:10:07,890
This was Carol's favorite beer.

180
00:10:09,210 --> 00:10:12,240
She always drank it out of the can, I should have known.

181
00:10:13,500 --> 00:10:15,100
Ross, let me ask you a question.

182
00:10:15,100 --> 00:10:19,580
She got the furniture, the stereo, the good TV-

183
00:10:19,580 --> 00:10:21,390
what did you get?

184
00:10:21,570 --> 00:10:22,210
You guys.

185
00:10:22,210 --> 00:10:23,630
- Oh, my God. - You got screwed.

186
00:10:23,630 --> 00:10:25,010
Oh my God!

187
00:10:25,010 --> 00:10:29,010  
- Oh my God! - I know, I know, I'm such an idiot.

188
00:10:29,350 --> 00:10:30,470
I guess I should have caught on when

189
00:10:30,470 --> 00:10:34,120
she started going to the dentist four and five times a week.

190
00:10:34,130 --> 00:10:36,380
I mean, how clean can teeth get?

191
00:10:36,530 --> 00:10:39,100
My brother's going through that right now, he's such a mess.

192
00:10:39,100 --> 00:10:40,810
How did you get through it?

193
00:10:40,810 --> 00:10:44,590
Well, you might try accidentally breaking something valuable of hers,

194
00:10:44,590 --> 00:10:46,360
- say her... - ...leg?

195
00:10:46,360 --> 00:10:49,460
That's one way! Me, I-

196
00:10:49,460 --> 00:10:50,930
I went for the watch.

197
00:10:50,930 --> 00:10:53,010
You actually broke her watch?

198
00:10:53,280 --> 00:10:56,720
Barry, I'm sorry... I am so sorry...

199
00:10:56,720 --> 00:10:58,290
I know you probably think that this is all about

200
00:10:58,290 --> 00:11:00,820
what I said the other day about you making love with your socks on,

201
00:11:00,820 --> 00:11:04,250
but it isn't... it isn't, it's about me, and I just...

202
00:11:11,530 --> 00:11:13,500
Hi, machine cut me off again...

203
00:11:13,500 --> 00:11:15,070
anyway...look, look,

204
00:11:16,390 --> 00:11:17,930
You know what the scariest part is?

205
00:11:17,930 --> 00:11:20,790
What if there's only one woman for everybody, y'know?

206
00:11:20,790 --> 00:11:22,550
I mean what if you get one woman-

207
00:11:22,550 --> 00:11:24,210
and that's it?

208
00:11:24,210 --> 00:11:28,870
Unfortunately in my case, there was only one woman- for her...

209
00:11:29,520 --> 00:11:32,690
What are you talking about? 'One woman'?

210
00:11:33,590 --> 00:11:37,390
That's like saying there's only one flavor of ice cream for you.

211
00:11:37,400 --> 00:11:40,680
Lemme tell you something, Ross. There's lots of flavors out there.

212
00:11:40,680 --> 00:11:46,210
There's Rocky Road, and Cookie Dough, and Bing! Cherry Vanilla.

213
00:11:46,360 --> 00:11:51,120
You could get 'em with Jimmies, or nuts, or whipped cream!

214
00:11:51,120 --> 00:11:53,880
This is the best thing that ever happened to you!

215
00:11:53,880 --> 00:11:57,300
You got married, you were, like, what, eight?

216
00:11:58,720 --> 00:12:02,450
Welcome back to the world! Grab a spoon!

217
00:12:02,830 --> 00:12:06,110
I honestly don't know if I'm hungry or horny.

218
00:12:06,110 --> 00:12:07,980
Stay out of my freezer!

219
00:12:10,920 --> 00:12:14,130
Ever since she walked out on me, I, uh...

220
00:12:14,580 --> 00:12:18,780
What?... What, you wanna spell it out with noodles?

221
00:12:18,780 --> 00:12:23,140
No, it's, it's more of a fifth date kinda revelation.

222
00:12:23,660 --> 00:12:27,780
Oh, so there is gonna be a fifth date?

223
00:12:27,780 --> 00:12:29,590
Isn't there?

224
00:12:29,630 --> 00:12:32,730
Yeah... yeah, I think there is.

225
00:12:33,230 --> 00:12:35,290
What were you gonna say?

226
00:12:37,120 --> 00:12:42,430
Well, ever-ev-... ever since she left me,

227
00:12:43,680 --> 00:12:47,170
um, I haven't been able to, uh, perform.

228
00:12:47,170 --> 00:12:48,730
...Sexually.

229
00:12:51,340 --> 00:12:53,140
Oh, God, Oh, God, I am sorry...

230
00:12:53,140 --> 00:12:54,610  
- I am so sorry... - It's okay...

231
00:12:54,610 --> 00:12:57,870
I know being spit on is probably not what you need right now.

232
00:12:58,060 --> 00:13:03,430
- Um... how long? - Two years.

233
00:13:03,710 --> 00:13:09,420
Wow! I'm-I'm-I'm glad you smashed her watch!

234
00:13:10,410 --> 00:13:14,790
So you still think you, um... might want that fifth date?

235
00:13:16,710 --> 00:13:20,170
...Yeah. Yeah, I do.

236
00:13:26,090 --> 00:13:31,210
Oh...see... but Joanne loved Chachi!

237
00:13:31,460 --> 00:13:33,690
That's the difference!

238
00:13:35,380 --> 00:13:36,990
Grab a spoon.

239
00:13:36,990 --> 00:13:40,290
Do you know how long it's been since I've grabbed a spoon?

240
00:13:40,290 --> 00:13:43,670
Do the words 'Billy, don't be a hero' mean anything to you?

241
00:13:40,290 --> 00:13:43,670
an3fs16bord0fnfad0,0b0pos374,247    70

242
00:13:45,290 --> 00:13:47,220
Y'know, here's the thing.

243
00:13:47,220 --> 00:13:51,760
Even if I could get it together enough to- to ask a woman out,...

244
00:13:52,870 --> 00:13:54,810
who am I gonna ask?

245
00:14:16,560 --> 00:14:17,960
Isn't this amazing?

246
00:14:17,960 --> 00:14:20,710
I mean, I have never made coffee before in my entire life.

247
00:14:20,710 --> 00:14:23,210
- That is amazing. - Congratulations.

248
00:14:23,210 --> 00:14:24,100
While you're on a roll

249
00:14:24,100 --> 00:14:27,530
If you feel like you have to make a Western omelet or something..

250
00:14:30,890 --> 00:14:33,210
Although actually I'm really not that hungry...

251
00:14:35,650 --> 00:14:38,090
- Morning. - Good morning.

252
00:14:39,760 --> 00:14:41,800  
- Morning. - Morning, Paul.

253
00:14:41,800 --> 00:14:44,460  
- Hello, Paul. - Hi, Paul, is it?

254
00:14:51,650 --> 00:14:54,540
- Thank you. Thank you so much. - Stop.

255
00:14:54,540 --> 00:14:55,780
We'll talk later.

256
00:15:02,100 --> 00:15:03,010
Yeah. Thank you.

257
00:15:09,790 --> 00:15:11,840
That wasn't a real date?!

258
00:15:13,190 --> 00:15:15,670
What the hell do you do on a real date?

259
00:15:16,950 --> 00:15:20,150
- Shut up, and put my table back. - Okayyy!

260
00:15:20,700 --> 00:15:22,780
All right, kids, I gotta get to work.

261
00:15:22,780 --> 00:15:24,870
If I don't input those numbers...

262
00:15:25,470 --> 00:15:27,940
it doesn't make much of a difference...

263
00:15:31,220 --> 00:15:34,200
So, like, you guys all have jobs?

264
00:15:34,200 --> 00:15:36,100
Yeah, we all have jobs.

265
00:15:36,100 --> 00:15:39,030
See, that's how we buy stuff.

266
00:15:40,280 --> 00:15:42,060
Yeah, I'm an actor.

267
00:15:42,190 --> 00:15:44,210
Wow! Would I have seen you in anything?

268
00:15:44,210 --> 00:15:46,750
I doubt it. Mostly regional work.

269
00:15:46,750 --> 00:15:48,650
Oh wait, wait, unless you happened to catch the

270
00:15:48,660 --> 00:15:50,620
Reruns' production of Pinocchio.

271
00:15:50,630 --> 00:15:53,760
'Look, Gippetto, I'm a real live boy.'

272
00:15:50,630 --> 00:15:53,760
an3fs16bord0fnfad0,0b0pos374,247

273
00:15:55,990 --> 00:15:59,640  
-  I will not take this abuse.  - You're right, I'm sorry.

274
00:16:00,090 --> 00:16:02,950
Once I was a wooden boy, a little wooden boy...

275
00:16:07,090 --> 00:16:08,710
So how you doing today?

276
00:16:08,710 --> 00:16:11,270
Did you sleep okay? Talk to Barry?

277
00:16:11,270 --> 00:16:13,370
I can't stop smiling.

278
00:16:13,830 --> 00:16:14,640
I can see that.

279
00:16:14,650 --> 00:16:17,420
You look like you slept with a hanger in your mouth.

280
00:16:23,060 --> 00:16:26,240
I know, he's just so, so...

281
00:16:26,460 --> 00:16:28,280
Do you remember you and Tony DeMarco?

282
00:16:28,280 --> 00:16:29,170
Oh, yeah.

283
00:16:29,170 --> 00:16:31,970
Well, it's like that. With feelings.

284
00:16:33,240 --> 00:16:35,440
-  
- Wow,are you in trouble!

285
00:16:35,440 --> 00:16:39,410
Okay. Okay. I am just going to get up, go to work

286
00:16:39,410 --> 00:16:41,540
and not think about him all day.

287
00:16:42,180 --> 00:16:45,030
Or else I'm just gonna get up and go to work.

288
00:16:45,240 --> 00:16:47,290
- Oh, look, wish me luck! - What for?

289
00:16:47,290 --> 00:16:51,120
I'm gonna go get one of those job things.

290
00:16:58,510 --> 00:17:00,050
Hey, Monica!

291
00:17:00,060 --> 00:17:01,370
Hey Frannie, welcome back!

292
00:17:01,370 --> 00:17:02,890
How was Florida?

293
00:17:02,920 --> 00:17:05,180
You had sex, didn't you?

294
00:17:06,340 --> 00:17:08,340
-
- How do you do that?

295
00:17:08,340 --> 00:17:10,590
So? Who?

296
00:17:10,590 --> 00:17:12,350
You know Paul?

297
00:17:12,790 --> 00:17:14,510
Paul the Wine Guy?

298
00:17:14,520 --> 00:17:16,510
Oh yeah, I know Paul.

299
00:17:18,660 --> 00:17:21,570
You mean you know Paul like I know Paul?

300
00:17:21,570 --> 00:17:24,000
Are you kidding? I take credit for Paul.

301
00:17:24,000 --> 00:17:28,600
Y'know before me, there was no snap in his turtle for two years.

302
00:17:31,280 --> 00:17:33,550
Of course it was a line!

303
00:17:34,130 --> 00:17:37,150
Why?! Why? Why, why would anybody do something like that?

304
00:17:37,150 --> 00:17:39,620
I assume we're looking for an answer more sophisticated

305
00:17:39,620 --> 00:17:42,440
than 'to get you into bed'.

306
00:17:43,380 --> 00:17:44,890
Is it me?

307
00:17:45,040 --> 00:17:47,830
Is it like I have some sort of beacon

308
00:17:47,830 --> 00:17:51,810
that only dogs and men with severe emotional problems can hear?

309
00:17:51,810 --> 00:17:53,940
All right, c'mere, gimme your feet.

310
00:18:01,220 --> 00:18:03,660
I just thought he was nice, y'know?

311
00:18:05,790 --> 00:18:08,650
I can't believe you didn't know it was a line!

312
00:18:13,040 --> 00:18:15,210
- Guess what?  - You got a job?

313
00:18:15,210 --> 00:18:18,380
Are you kidding? I'm trained for nothing!

314
00:18:19,820 --> 00:18:22,120
I was laughed out of twelve interviews today.

315
00:18:22,120 --> 00:18:23,960
And yet you're surprisingly upbeat.

316
00:18:23,960 --> 00:18:27,370
You would be too if you found John and David boots on sale,

317
00:18:27,380 --> 00:18:29,280
fifty percent off!

318
00:18:29,610 --> 00:18:32,850
Oh, how well you know me...

319
00:18:32,850 --> 00:18:34,710
They're my new 'I don't need a job,

320
00:18:34,710 --> 00:18:37,720
I don't need my parents, I've got great boots' boots!

321
00:18:39,100 --> 00:18:40,650
How'd you pay for them?

322
00:18:40,650 --> 00:18:42,030
Uh, credit card.

323
00:18:42,030 --> 00:18:43,830
And who pays for that?

324
00:18:44,150 --> 00:18:46,410
Um... my... father.

325
00:18:48,860 --> 00:18:50,950
C'mon, you can't live off your parents your whole life.

326
00:18:50,950 --> 00:18:54,450
I know that. That's why I was getting married.

327
00:18:55,460 --> 00:18:58,580
Give her a break, it's hard being on your own for the first time.

328
00:18:58,580 --> 00:18:59,320
Thank you.

329
00:18:59,320 --> 00:19:01,850
You're welcome. I remember when I first came to this city.

330
00:19:01,850 --> 00:19:02,900
I was fourteen.

331
00:19:02,910 --> 00:19:05,910
My mom had just killed herself and my step-dad was back in prison,

332
00:19:05,910 --> 00:19:08,230
and I got here, and I didn't know anybody.

333
00:19:08,230 --> 00:19:10,630
And I ended up living with this albino guy who was, like,

334
00:19:10,630 --> 00:19:13,040
cleaning windshields outside port authority,

335
00:19:13,040 --> 00:19:14,900
and then he killed himself,

336
00:19:16,370 --> 00:19:18,000
and then I found aromatherapy.

337
00:19:18,010 --> 00:19:20,980
So believe me, I know exactly how you feel.

338
00:19:24,420 --> 00:19:27,240
The word you're looking for is

339
00:19:27,700 --> 00:19:29,520
Anyway...

340
00:19:33,170 --> 00:19:34,390
All right, you ready?

341
00:19:34,390 --> 00:19:35,310
-
- I don't think so.

342
00:19:35,310 --> 00:19:41,530
C'mon, cut. Cut, cut, cut,...

343
00:19:45,710 --> 00:19:47,660
Welcome to the real world!

344
00:19:47,660 --> 00:19:50,340
It sucks. You're gonna love it!

345
00:19:57,340 --> 00:20:00,870
Well, that's it. You gonna crash on the couch?

346
00:20:00,870 --> 00:20:03,340
No. No, I gotta go home sometime.

347
00:20:03,570 --> 00:20:05,320
- You be okay?  - Yeah.

348
00:20:07,050 --> 00:20:09,760
Hey Mon, look what I just found on the floor.

349
00:20:11,120 --> 00:20:12,580
What?

350
00:20:12,940 --> 00:20:14,900
That's Paul's watch.

351
00:20:14,900 --> 00:20:19,510
You just put it back where you found it. Oh boy

352
00:20:19,510 --> 00:20:23,130
- Alright. Goodnight, everybody.  - Goodnight.

353
00:20:34,950 --> 00:20:35,620  
- Sorry-  - No no no, go-

354
00:20:35,620 --> 00:20:36,810
No, you have it, really, I don't want it

355
00:20:36,810 --> 00:20:39,190
- Split it?  - Okay.

356
00:20:43,490 --> 00:20:44,550
You know you probably didn't know this,

357
00:20:44,550 --> 00:20:46,850
but back in high school, I had a, um,

358
00:20:47,420 --> 00:20:49,640
major crush on you.

359
00:20:50,460 --> 00:20:51,980
I knew.

360
00:20:52,170 --> 00:20:53,880
You did! Oh....

361
00:20:55,360 --> 00:20:56,340
I always figured you just thought

362
00:20:56,340 --> 00:20:59,060
I was Monica's geeky older brother.

363
00:20:59,060 --> 00:20:59,700
I did.

364
00:21:05,530 --> 00:21:07,090
Oh. Listen, do you think

365
00:21:07,600 --> 00:21:09,880
and try not to let my intense vulnerability

366
00:21:09,880 --> 00:21:12,070
become any kind of a factor here

367
00:21:13,020 --> 00:21:15,200
but do you think it would be okay if I asked you out?

368
00:21:15,200 --> 00:21:17,010
Sometime? Maybe?

369
00:21:18,250 --> 00:21:21,860
Yeah, maybe...

370
00:21:22,950 --> 00:21:31,530
Okay... okay, maybe I will...

371
00:21:35,890 --> 00:21:37,450
- Goodnight.  - Goodnight.

372
00:21:51,470 --> 00:21:52,910
See ya....

373
00:21:54,970 --> 00:21:58,180
Waitwait, what's the deal?

374
00:21:59,560 --> 00:22:01,840
I just grabbed a spoon.

375
00:22:10,490 --> 00:22:12,120
I can't believe what I'm hearing here.

376
00:22:12,120 --> 00:22:14,040
I can't believe what I'm hearing here...

377
00:22:14,040 --> 00:22:14,940
What? I-I said you had a

378
00:22:14,940 --> 00:22:16,850
What I said you had...

379
00:22:17,390 --> 00:22:18,910
Would you stop?

380
00:22:18,910 --> 00:22:21,420
- Oh, was I doing it again?  - Yes!

381
00:22:22,710 --> 00:22:25,550
Would anybody like more coffee?

382
00:22:26,780 --> 00:22:29,220
Did you make it, or are you just serving it?

383
00:22:29,220 --> 00:22:31,680  
- I'm just serving it.  - Yeah. Yeah, I'll have a cup of coffee.

384
00:22:33,050 --> 00:22:34,680
Kids, new dream...

385
00:22:35,040 --> 00:22:36,310
I'm in Las Vegas.

386
00:22:36,310 --> 00:22:38,060
I'm Liza Minelli-

387
00:22:36,310 --> 00:22:38,060
an8bord1fs18b1

388
00:00:02,480 --> 00:00:06,440
fad500,500fnb1fs43pos187.945,207.436
fs16

389
00:00:06,980 --> 00:00:12,160
an3fnshad0bord0
i1So no one told you life was gonna be this way

390
00:00:12,160 --> 00:00:14,280
an3fnshad0bord0  
i1your jobs a joke, you're broke,

391
00:00:14,280 --> 00:00:17,270
an3fnshad0bord0
i1your love life's D.O.A.

392
00:00:17,270 --> 00:00:21,570
an3fnshad0bord0
i1It's like you're always stuck in second gear,

393
00:00:21,670 --> 00:00:24,720
an3fnshad0bord0
i1And it hasn't been your day, your week, your month,

394
00:00:24,720 --> 00:00:27,330
an3fnshad0bord0
i1or even your year, but

395
00:00:27,330 --> 00:00:30,630
an3fnshad0bord0
i1I'll be there for you,

396
00:00:30,630 --> 00:00:32,360
an3fnshad0bord0
i1when the rain starts to pour.

397
00:00:32,580 --> 00:00:35,560
an3fnshad0bord0
i1I'll be there for you,

398
00:00:35,560 --> 00:00:37,500
an3fnshad0bord0
i1like I've been there before.

399
00:00:37,500 --> 00:00:40,730
an3fnshad0bord0
i1I'll be there for you,

400
00:00:40,730 --> 00:00:44,190
an3fnshad0bord0
i1'cause you're there for me too.

