(BELL RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
I wish you wouldn't do that around me.
It's so filthy!
Don't give me a problem
about the cigarettes.
It's such a filthy habit.
Oh, my God!
Look at this.
Oh, Jesus. Oh, this is so appalling.
GEORGE: Oh, I can't believe it.
I can't believe they gave it to him.
(CAR LOCKS)
HARRY: Ah, this is pathetic.
Now he's a loser with a Jaguar.
Seriously, who did he have to blow
to get that thing?
- GEORGE: Good morning, sir.
- Mr. Willis.
It's really a É
HARRY: Mr. Trask!
Quite a piece of machinery.
- Good morning, Havemeyer.
- Morning to you, sir.
Bene!
- Bene?
- Bene! Fabulous!
What's fabulous?
That fine piece of steel you have back there.
Ah, you don't think I deserve it.
No, sir. On the contrary.
I think it's great.
Why should the headmaster of Baird
be seen putt-putting
around in some junker?
In fact, I think
the board of trustees have had
their first true stroke
of inspiration in some time.
Well, thank you, Havemeyer.
I'll take that at face value.
I'd expect nothing less, sir.
Have a good day.
- Morning, Mrs. Hunsaker.
- Good morning.
What have we here, Murderer's Row?
What was that about?
Nothing. Just saying hello.
I like to say hello to Headmaster Trask.
Sugarbush. Lift tickets and condo vouchers.
I thought we were going to Stowe.
Sugarbush is Stowe, Jimmy.
HARRY: This year we're doing it right.
Thanksgiving in Vermont,
Christmas in Switzerland É
- Christmas in Gstaad is gonna cost us É
- "Staad."
The "G" is silent.
"Staad." George?
- "Staad."
- Trent?
- "Staad," man.
- So what about Staad?
Fine. The "G" may be silent,
but it's gonna take at least
three grand to get there.
I'll have to talk to my father.
Better yet, have my father talk to your father.
Or my father talk to your father.
You going home this weekend, Chas?
I don't know.
You going home to fuckin' Idaho
for Thanksgiving?
I'm from Oregon.
I meant fuckin' Oregon.
Charlie, how do you feel about skiing?
(LAUGHING)
You in the mood for
the white-bosomed slopes of Vermont?
Got a deal going.
20% off for my friends.
My father set it up.
Christmas in Switzerland.
- Staad.
- Gstaad. Dropping the "G" is phony.
You said everybody says "Staad."
Not if you've been there.
Easter in Bermuda,
then Kentucky Derby weekend.
We could fit you in, kid.
Well, how much are
these white-bosomed slopes of Vermont?
1,200.
Includes a nine-course,
champagne Thanksgiving dinner.
$1,200 is a little rich for my blood, Harry.
Well, how short are you?
How short, Harry?
So short it wouldn't be worth the trouble
of you and George to measure.
But thanks for askin', all right?
Mmm-hmm.
If you change your mind É
What'd you do that for?
You know he's on aid.
On major holidays, Willis,
it's customary for the lord of the manor
to offer drippings to the poor.
You're so full of shit!
(DOORBELL RINGS)
Hi. Mrs. Rossi?
Yes?
I'm here about the weekend job.
Come on in.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
Does he got pimples? He hates pimples.
Francine, be quiet.
Pimples. Pimples. Yeah.
Shush!
I'm sorry. The school gave me your name,
but I've forgotten it.
It's Charlie Simms.
- How are you, Charlie?
- Fine, thanks.
Right this way.
You're available the whole weekend?
Yeah.
- Not going home for Thanksgiving?
- No.
Good.
They put him in a veteran's home,
but he hated it,
so I told my dad that we'd take him.
Before you go in,
do you mind my telling you a few things?
Don't "sir" him
and don't ask him too many questions.
And if he staggers a little when he gets up,
don't pay any attention.
(SIGHS) Charlie, I can tell
you're the right person for the job.
And Uncle Frank's gonna like you a lot, too.
Where you gonna be this weekend?
Oh, we're driving to Albany.
Donny, my husband, has family there.
Do you want Tommy in or out?
FRANK: Leave him out!
He's chasing that Calico ginch
from the track houses again!
Down deep, the man is a lump of sugar.
Sir?
FRANK: Don't call me sir.
(STAMMERING) I'm sorry.
I mean mister, sir.
Uh-oh, we got a moron here, is that it?
No, mister É
That is É
(STAMMERING) Lieutenant. Yes, sir É
Lieutenant Colonel.
Twenty-six years on the line,
nobody ever busted me four grades before.
Get in here, you idiot!
Come a little closer.
I wanna get a better look at you.
How's your skin, son?
My skin, sir?
Oh, for Christ's sake.
- I'm sorry, I don É
- Just call me Frank.
Call me Mr. Slade.
Call me Colonel, if you must.
Just don't call me sir.
All right, Colonel.
Simms, Charles.
A senior.
You on student aid, Simms?
Yes, I am.
For "student aid" read "crook."
Your father peddles car telephones
at a 300% markup.
Your mother works on heavy commission
in a camera store.
Graduated to it from espresso machines.
(LAUGHS)
What are you,
dying of some wasting disease?
No, I'm right É I'm right here.
I know exactly where your body is.
What I'm lookin' for is
some indication of a brain.
Too much football without a helmet?
Hah! Lyndon's line on Gerry Ford.
Deputy Debriefer, Paris, Peace Talks, '68.
Snagged the Silver Star and a silver bar.
Threw me into G-2.
G-2?
Intelligence, of which you have none.
(YELLING) Where you from?
Gresham, Oregon,
Colonel.
What does your daddy do
in Gresham, Oregon?
Hmm? Count wood chips?
My stepfather and my mom
run a convenience store.
How convenient. What time they open?
5:00 a.m.
Close?
1:00 a.m.
Hard workers.
You got me all misty-eyed!
So, what are you doing here
in this sparrow-fart town?
(STAMMERING) I attend Baird.
Attend Baird!
I know you go to the Baird school.
Point is, how do you afford it,
even with the student aid
and the folks back home hustlin' corn nuts?
(SIGHS) I won a Young American
merit scholarship.
Hoo-ah!
(SINGING) Glory, glory
Hallelujah
Glory, glory
(KNOCKING)
Who's there?
That little piece of tail?
Get her outta here!
(FRANCINE GIGGLING)
Yeah.
Can't believe they're my blood.
IQ of sloths and the manners of banshees.
He's a mechanic, she's a homemaker.
He knows as much about cars
as a beauty queen,
and she bakes cookies, taste like wing nuts.
As for the tots, they're twits.
How's your skin, son?
I like my aides to be presentable.
Well, I É
I've had a few zits.
But my roommate, he lent me his Clinique
because he's from Chestnut Hill
and he's got É
"The History of My Skin," by Charles Simms.
You patronizing me, peewee? Hmm?
You givin' me that old prep school palaver?
Baird School!
A bunch of runny-nosed snots
in tweed jackets
all studyin' to be George Bush.
Well É
I believe President Bush
went to Andover, Colonel.
You sharpshootin' me, punk?
Is that what you're doin'?
Don't you sharpshoot me.
You'll give me 40.
Then you're gonna give me 40 more.
Then you're gonna pull K.P., the grease pit!
I'll rub your nose in enlisted men's crud
till you don't know which end is up!
You understand?
Yeah.
What do you want?
What do you mean, what do I want?
What do you want here?
I want a job.
A job!
Yeah, I want a job so I can make, you know,
(CLEARS THROAT)
my plane fare home for Christmas.
Oh, God, you're touching!
WOMAN ON RADIO: (SINGING)
They used to waltz on the banks
Of the mighty Mississippi
Loving the whole night through
Till the riverboat gambler
Went off to make a killin'
And bring it on back to you
(MUSIC STOPS)
Still here, poormouth? Hmm?
Convenience store, my ass!
Hustlin' jalapeno dips to the appleseeds.
Go on.
Dismissed.
Dismissed!
(RADIO PLAYING)
Evangeline
- (CHILDREN CHATTERING)
- CHARLIE: Mrs. Rossi?
Charlie, we're up here! Come on up.
- This is Donny.
- Hey, Charlie.
Hi.
Mrs. Rossi, I got the feelin' I screwed up.
Oh, you couldn't have.
It was a bad interview.
That was no interview, Charlie. You're it.
You're the only one that showed up.
You have to take the job.
He sleeps a lot. You can watch television,
call your girlfriend.
I promise you, an easy 300 bucks.
(SIGHS) I don't get an easy feeling.
(SIGHS)
His bark is worse than his bite.
He was a great soldier, a real hero.
The man grows on you.
By Sunday night, you'll be best friends.
(SIGHS) Charlie, please.
I want to get away with my husband
for a few days,
and Uncle Frank won't come with us.
Six months ago,
he could sometimes tell light from dark,
but now there's nothing.
I just feel better having
someone else around just in case.
Please?
Okay, Mrs. Rossi.
Sure.
(SIGHS) Thank you, Charlie.
Come here, you.
There you go.
GEORGE: Chas. Chas, hold up.
- How you doin'?
- I'm good.
That's great.
This can't go out. This is on reserve.
Here's the thing.
I need the book tonight
for a Thanksgiving quiz
with big-shit Preston in the morning.
Yeah, I know.
That's why he put it on reserve.
This is our only copy.
Chas, I'm pullin' an all-nighter.
Without that book I'm dead, okay?
If it's not back by 7:30, it's gonna be my ass.
Oh, I promise. I promise.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
Just a second. I gotta lock up.
Okay.
God, can you wait
to get out of this dump or what?
Where you guys going skiing again?
Sugarloaf or É
It's bush, Chas, Sugarbush.
(LAUGHS) That's my boys.
(WHISTLES) What are you doin'?
Keep your voice down!
I'll tell you about it in the morning.
(SHUSHING)
What É
Mrs. Hunsaker, have a nice day?
George, why all the noise?
(CHUCKLING)
(WHISPERING) It's Hunsaker! Go! Go!
I was just messin' around with Chas.
Good evening, Charles.
Hi, Mrs. Hunsaker.
- What was that?
- I don't know, ma'am.
Who were those boys?
- Oh, who knows?
- What were they doing?
Charles?
Did you make this scarf yourself?
No, George, I bought it.
- 'Cause it's a beauty. It really is.
- Thank you, George.
In case I don't see you
before the Thanksgiving holidays,
why don't you give me
one of your big hugs?
- Oh, George!
- Please?
- Good evening, boys.
- Come on.
Goodbye, Mrs. Hunsaker.
JIMMY ON LOUDSPEAKER:
Mr. Trask is our fearless leader,
a man of learning, a voracious reader.
He could recite the Iliad in ancient Greek
while fishing for trout in a rippling creek.
Endowed with wisdom, of judgment sound,
nevertheless about him
the questions abound.
(HISSING)
HARRY: How does Mr. Trask
make such wonderful deals?
Why did the trustees
buy him Jaguar wheels?
He wasn't conniving.
He wasn't crass.
He merely puckered his lips
and kissed their ass!
(BOYS LAUGHING)
Come on.
One more.
One more, come on!
(BOYS WHISTLING AND CHEERING)
Fuck you!
TRASK: Mr. Simms, Mr. Willis.
Mrs. Hunsaker says that you gentlemen
were at a vantage point last night
to observe who was responsible for this
stunt.
Who was it?
I really couldn't tell you, sir.
I thought I saw someone
fooling with the lamppost,
but by the time I pulled focus,
they were gone.
Mr. Simms?
I couldn't say.
That automobile is not just
a possession of mine.
That automobile was presented to me
by the board of trustees.
It is a symbol of the standard of excellence
for which this school is known,
and I will not have it tarnished.
The automobile?
The standard, Mr. Willis.
What's your position, Mr. Simms?
On what, sir?
On preserving the reputation of Baird.
(STAMMERING) I'm for Baird.
Then, who did it?
I really couldn't say for sure.
Very well.
First thing Monday,
I'm convening a special session
of the student-faculty
disciplinary committee.
As this is a matter which concerns
the whole school,
the entire student body will be present.
There will be no classes, no activities.
Nothing will transpire at this institution
until that proceeding is concluded.
And if, at that time,
we are no further along than we are now,
I will expel you both.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Mr. Willis, would you excuse us?
Have a nice Thanksgiving.
Thank you. You, too, Mr. Willis.
I will.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Mr. Simms,
I'm not quite through with you yet.
One of the few perks of this office is that
I am empowered to handle certain matters
on my own as I see fit.
Do you understand?
- Yes, sir.
- Good.
The Dean of Admissions at Harvard
and I have an arrangement.
Along with the usual sheaf of applicants
submitted by Baird,
of which virtually two-thirds are
guaranteed admittance,
I add one name,
somebody who's a standout
and yet underprivileged.
A student who cannot afford to pay
the board and tuition in Cambridge.
Do you know on whose behalf
I drafted a memo this year?
No, sir.
You.
You, Mr. Simms.
Now can you tell me who did it?
(SIGHS) No, sir, I can't.
You take the weekend
to think about it, Mr. Simms.
Good afternoon.
What'd he say?
- Nothin'.
- What do you mean, nothing?
He said the same thing. He just said it over.
You know what he's doing?
He's good-cop, bad-coppin' us.
He knows I'm old guard. You're fringe.
He's gonna bear down on me
and soft-soap you.
(LAUGHING) Did he try to soft-soap you?
Did he?
No.
Chas, I detect a slight panic pulse from you.
Are you panicking?
Yeah, a little.
Come on. You're on scholarship, right?
Yeah.
You're on scholarship from Oregon at Baird.
You're a long way from home, Chas.
What's that got to do with anything?
I don't know how it works out there.
But how it works here?
We stick together.
It's us against them, no matter what.
We don't cover our ass.
We don't tell our parents.
Stonewall everybody!
And above all, never, ever
leave any of us twisting in the wind.
And that's it.
What does that have to do with
me being on scholarship?
Hey, hey.
I'm just tryin' to bring you up to speed, kid,
that's it.
Thanks.
I'll tell you what.
Give me a few hours
to figure out the moves,
and call me tonight in Vermont.
I'll be at the Sugarbush lodge, all right?
All right.
You all right?
Yeah, I guess so.
Okay.
Try to keep him down to four drinks a day.
If you can keep him down to 40,
you're doin' good.
We try to water them down a little.
Do you know how to do that?
It's a long ride, honey.
Get the bags in the car. I'll be right out.
Mommy, Mommy,
don't forget Uncle Frank's walk.
KAREN: Oh, yeah.
You have to air him out a little every day.
Why don't you go on back there,
get yourself oriented?
I'll come out in a minute,
give you telephone numbers and stuff.
FRANK: Well, I wouldn't try a thing like that
unless I knew, would I?
Just let me speak to her.
Hello, beautiful. Is that you?
Yeah, we spoke yesterday.
(CHUCKLING)
You have a glass of wine with lunch?
You sound a little dusky. Hmm.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Just a minute, sweetheart.
You're back, huh?
Tenacious!
Get out my dress blues.
They're in a garment bag in the closet.
Check the top dresser drawer.
Take out the shoulder boards
and affix them, shoulders right and left,
ASAP. That means now.
Hello.
Sorry to keep you waiting, sweetheart.
I'm not the kind of guy
who likes to rush things,
but I'm catchin' a 4:00 at Logan,
I'm lookin' out my window,
and there's not a taxi in sight.
What happened to Chet?
He didn't invest in a radio yet?
Hah!
Well, get your driver on it.
Tell him to get a move on.
Yes. Mmm.
Some kind of body has got to
go with that bedroom voice.
One day I'm gonna swing by,
get a better look at it.
You bet.
Bye.
My Valpak's underneath the bed.
Get it out.
Put the boards on the blues and fold 'em in.
Are we going someplace, Colonel?
What business is that of yours?
Don't shrug, imbecile. I'm blind.
Save your body language for the bimbi.
Now, get my gear out.
KAREN: Francine, get in the car.
It's almost 3:00.
The goddamn Flintstones haven't left yet.
DONNY: Willie Rossi must go in the car.
Here comes Mrs. Rossi now.
Damn it!
She said goodbye to me three times today.
What has she got, separation anxiety?
Cut her off at the door.
Hi, honey. Bye, honey.
I wish you were coming with us.
Me, too.
Maybe next time.
- Drive carefully now.
- Yeah.
Charlie, this is where we'll be.
Good luck, Charlie.
Don't let him drink too much.
See you, Charlie.
And no 900 numbers. He loves to talk dirty.
FRANK: All right, let's get to work.
L-buckles givin' you trouble?
Never in the Boy Scouts, sluggo?
I made Tenderfoot.
Tenderfoot, my foot!
Convenience store mama's boy.
Here. Let me take a look at that.
Touch me again, I'll kill you,
you little son of a bitch!
I touch you.
Understand?
My shoulder boards are in
the top dresser drawer.
Get them, son.
The epaulets with the silver oak leaf.
Are these the É
Good. Taxi come yet?
Colonel, where are we going?
Where are we going?
Freak show central.
- Where's that?
- New York City.
That's in New York, son.
New York State.
Mrs. Rossi didn't say anything to me
about going anywhere.
She forgot.
Should we call her, 'cause I É
You kidding me?
Call her? By the time they get to Albany
in that Hupmobile he drives
it'll be opening day at Saratoga.
Colonel, I can't go to New York City.
Why not?
New York É
New York's too much responsibility.
Ah, responsibility!
I had a lot of 17-year-olds
in my first platoon.
I took care of them. All set!
How do I look?
Tickets. Money.
Speech.
Old Washington joke
from my days with Lyndon.
(CAR HONKING)
(EXCLAIMS) I knew I could count
on transportation.
Are you ready?
This is not Panmunjom.
A simple yes will do.
- Um É
- Good! Here you go.
Come on! Hop to, son!
You're in front of me. Let's go.
(MEOWING)
Tomster, come here, boy.
Come on.
Here, Tomster, come on.
Tomster, Tomster. Yeah.
Remember, when in doubt,
fuck.
Good afternoon, sir.
Where's our destination?
Our destination,
New York City, home of the brave!
We got two for the shuttle to New York.
I'm not shuttling anywhere.
Look at those tickets. First class.
Yes, sir, first class.
Colonel, you bought me a ticket?
I never said I'd go to New York.
Oh, what are you, some kind of chicken-shit,
sticks to job description only?
Gate 46, sir.
As you were, son.
Thank you, sir.
Which way's the door?
Are you blind? Are you blind?
Of course not.
Then why do you keep grabbin'
my goddamn arm?
I take your arm.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
How would you know,
watchin' MTV all your life?
- Gentlemen?
- Yeah!
- Jack Daniels.
- You bet.
And Diet Slice.
The old Diet Slice.
And a water.
- Thank you, Daphne.
- Certainly, sir.
(SIGHS LOUDLY)
- Mmm!
- How did you know her name?
Well, she's wearin' Floris.
That's an English cologne.
But her voice is California chickie.
Now, California chickie
bucking for English lady.
I call her Daphne.
Oh, big things may happen
to that little thing of yours.
Look, Colonel,
- I'll get you to New York, all right?
- Uh-huh.
Then I'm gonna have to
turn around and come back.
Well, Chuck,
you gotta do what you gotta do.
Charlie, all right?
Or Charles.
Sorry. I can't blame you, though.
Chuck is a É
So, why are we going to New York?
All information will be given
on a need-to-know basis.
Hoo-ah.
Where's Daphne? Let's get her down here.
She's in the back.
A tail's in the tail.
Hah!
Oh, but I still smell her.
(SNIFFING)
Women.
What can you say?
Who made 'em?
God must have been a fuckin' genius.
The hair É
They say the hair is everything, you know.
Have you ever buried your nose
in a mountain of curls
and just wanted to go to sleep forever?
Or lips,
and when they touched, yours were like
that first swallow of wine
after you just crossed the desert.
Tits!
Hoo-ah.
Big ones, little ones,
nipples staring right out at you
like secret searchlights.
Mmm.
And legs É
I don't care if they're Greek columns
or secondhand Steinways.
What's between 'em,
passport to heaven.
I need a drink.
Yes, Mr. Simms,
there's only two syllables
in this whole wide world worth hearing.
Pussy.
Hah!
Are you listening to me, son?
I'm givin' you pearls here.
(LAUGHS)
I guess you really like women.
Oh, above all things!
A very, very distant second
is a Ferrari.
Charlie?
Give me your hand.
This is just the start of your education, son.
Hoo-ah.
Where are we?
Where are we, eh?
The cynosure of all things civilized.
The Waldorf-Astoria.
The last time I was here, Charlie,
was with a G-2 from Brussels.
Had a Ferrari.
Every day I held the door open
for the fucker.
Never even offered me a ride.
Well, fuck him.
He's dead and I'm blind.
Spread the word.
Thank you, sir.
And the intelligence will be forthcoming?
Sir?
On the escort scene.
Yes, sir.
And welcome to the Waldorf.
Gracias, amigo.
Puerto Ricans.
Always made the best infantrymen.
(CLINKING)
Oh!
I'm home again.
Give me an inventory on this, will you?
All right, where am I, in Asia?
He told me the phone was on
the other side of the room, didn't he?
By the windows?
It's right here.
Okay.
We're in business.
Get me the Oak Room.
How's that inventory comin'?
There's Jim Beam
and Early Times.
Quartermaster's on the take again.
Hello. Is Sheldon or Mack there?
This is Lieutenant Colonel Frank Slade.
I used to be a regular.
I used to come in with a General Garbisch.
Yes, that's probably because
he's at Arlington, six feet under.
Listen up. I want a table for two,
and I don't mean Siberia,
8:15.
Clear them little bottles off.
And when I get off the phone,
call up Hyman.
Tell him I want it wall to wall
with John Daniels.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Don't you mean Jack Daniels?
He may be Jack to you, son. But when
you've known him as long as I have É
That's a joke. Hello!
This is Lieutenant Colonel Frank Slade.
I would like a limo,
8:00.
What are you drinkin'?
Nothing, thanks. I don't use it.
What's useful about it?
I don't know.
Listen, Colonel, I have to get going.
Where you goin'?
Back to school. I've got some real
important stuff I have to take care of.
Very well.
But I never let my aides leave
on an empty stomach.
You'll dine with me
and then my driver will transport you
to the airport for the Boston shuttle
departing at 2200 hours.
Meanwhile, unpack my bag.
I'm gonna christen the latrine.
FRANK: What's your name, driver?
Manny, sir.
Manny. The bellhops at the Waldorf,
are they any good at getting escorts?
I wouldn't know, sir.
What would you know?
About what?
About you-know-what?
Maybe I could manage something.
FRANK: I'm talkin' top of the line, now.
Let me think about this, sir.
(SIGHS)
What's the matter with you?
With me?
Yeah. Car feels heavy. You know why?
You got the fuckin' weight of the world
on your shoulders.
(SIGHS)
I got a little problem at school, that's all.
Spit it out!
It's not a big deal, all right?
Where we going,
the Oak Room or somethin'?
If it's not a big deal,
why did you say real important stuff?
What are you doin',
banging the dean's daughter? Hah!
I'm just in a little trouble.
What kind of trouble?
I saw some guys doing something.
To tell or not to tell, or it's your ass.
Hmm?
How'd you know that?
I'm a wizard. Give me the details, come on.
(SIGHS)
There's this guy at school named Harry.
He's this real rich kid,
and he like, runs the show.
Who else?
There's another guy, George,
but George didn't do anything.
George and I saw Harry and his buddies
doin' somethin'.
Now, the folks at Baird,
they know you and George
can identify the guilty parties?
Yeah, they think we can.
George is a friend of yours.
He's not a friend, but he's all right.
You trust him?
Yeah, I guess so.
He's on scholarship, too?
No, why?
We got George, we got Harry,
we got trouble.
They're rich, you're poor.
You wanna get rich.
You wanna graduate Baird,
become a rich big shot like them.
- Am I right?
- No.
It's not that way at all.
Okay, Charlie!
Here we are, gentlemen, the Oak Room.
The Oak Room!
Bring us a menu
and double Jack Daniels on the rocks.
Charlie, sit down here.
Perhaps you'll feel more
comfortable in this, sir.
(WHISTLES) You look great!
Thank you.
Here we are, Charlie, the Oak Room.
Now, read me the bill of fare.
Let's see.
You got the Oak Room
burger and fries for $24.
Where's the booze?
Flowin' like mud around here.
A $24 hamburger?
What's the story?
What story?
Are you a rich miser or something?
Hah!
No, I'm just your average blind man.
Your average blind man.
How do you plan on
paying for all this stuff?
Crisp, clean dollars.
American.
I saved up my disability checks.
How much did you save?
I mean, we flew first class,
we're at the Waldorf-Astoria,
a $24 hamburger restaurant.
All part of a plan, Charlie.
You want to let me in on it?
Why should I?
You're not interested. You don't give a shit!
You're leavin' on that last shuttle
out of LaGuardia.
Hmm? Ooh!
You got 15 minutes, son.
I don't think you're gonna make it.
Unless the Oak Room keeps some
complimentary helicopter on the roof.
No, sir. No!
You're here till tomorrow.
You said the last shuttle
leaves at 2200 hours.
That's 10:00, right?
Last I heard, yeah.
It's only 8:30.
I lied. Leaves at 9:00.
It leaves at 9:00?
Calm down. Calm down.
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
The truth is, Charlie,
I need a guide dog
to help me execute my plan.
What plan?
You have a right to know.
It's not really a plan, Charlie. It's sort of a É
More like a tour,
a little tour of pleasures.
Stay in a first-class hotel,
eat an agreeable meal,
drink a nice glass of wine,
see my big brother.
Nothing like family, you know.
And then, make love to a terrific woman.
After that É
Yeah?
I'm gonna lie down on
my big, beautiful bed at the Waldorf
and blow my brains out.
May I tell you our specials?
You may, sir.
Tonight we have charred venison with
buckwheat spaetzle and green peppercorn.
Grilled veal paillards,
tomato tapenade, and roasted eggplants.
Get me a napkin. My mouth's watering.
If you would like our
crème soufflé for dessert,
it would be a good idea to order now.
Yes, on the soufflŽ.
Give us a half a minute on the rest.
Very good, sir.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm leaning towards the spaetzle.
- Colonel Slade É
- Charlie, rolls on the table?
Give 'em to me.
You should try these rolls, Charlie.
I used to dream about them
when I was at Fort Huachuca.
- Colonel Slade É
- Bread's no good west of the Colorado.
Water's too alkaline.
Colonel Slade, did you say É
(SNIFFING)
Did I hear you right?
You said you're gonna kill yourself?
No.
I said I was gonna blow my brains out.
Try one of these rolls, Charlie.
I buttered it for you.
I don't want a roll, all right?
Okay. Have a radish!
Hah!
Hello! Bring me a double Jack Daniels
on the rocks.
Yes, sir. Right away.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(MOUTHING)
Please, don't do that.
Don't do that.
Hmm.
(SNIFFING)
What a marvelous place.
Okay.
Yeah.
Your billet is here.
You'll find bedding
in the closet on the shelf.
In the morning, the area will be
returned to sitting-room mode
no later than 0700 hours.
What was that?
Nothing.
Next time snap it out!
Thumb to palm, index finger
through little digit, smartly aligned,
sharp to the hairline, down!
Too many men, far better than you,
have executed that courtesy.
And if you're smart, you won't try it again.
This bat has got sharper radar
than the Nautilus.
Don't fuck with me, Charlie.
See you get a good night's sleep, son.
(GROANING)
FRANK: (SINGING) It's a lovely day today
So, whatever you gotta do
You got a lovely day to do it in, that's true
Good morning, Charlie.
(SIGHS) Good morning.
This is Sofia, Charlie.
She's a magician with a needle.
Sofia's workin' me up
a little Glen Plaid number,
and I've asked her if she'd
put something together for you.
I don't need any clothes, Colonel.
Standard issue
for an upscale urban assignment.
You don't like the clothes, Charlie,
on completion of duty,
you can give 'em away.
Juice, coffee, and other assorted goodies
on the trolley over there.
Get yourself up, get yourself together.
(SINGING) It's a great day for singin' a song
And it's a great day for movin' along
And it's a great day from morning to night
And it's a great day
For everybody's plight
(FRANK CHUCKLING)
How are you feeling today, Colonel?
Super!
Superior!
Superfluous!
Young Sofie here is working Thanksgiving
because she's trying to
put herself through college.
I told her, "My young friend Charlie's
headed for college."
Excuse me.
Where you goin'?
I need to use the phone.
What's wrong with the phones in here?
I don't want to disturb you.
You're not disturbing me. Make your call.
I'd kind of like to be private.
Stay out of my room!
This is as private as you're gonna get.
FRANK: (SINGING) But if you've got
somethin' that must be done
And it can only be done by one
Sofia,
what are the chances
of suitin' you up sometime?
- WOMAN: Sugarbush Lodge.
- George Willis, please.
GEORGE: Hello.
George! Hey, it's Charlie.
Hey, Chas.
Next year you gotta come up with us.
White powder on a base of snow bunnies.
Chas, are you there?
Yeah, I'm here.
You told me to call you for the moves.
All right.
For now, the move's no move, status quo.
Everything's the way we left it.
How did we leave it?
See no evil, hear no evil.
You know what I mean, Chas?
Yeah. See no evil, hear no evil.
Okay, then, walk like you talk.
All right, bye.
George Willis, huh?
Yeah.
George Willis.
That makes his father
probably George Willis, Senior.
Charlie, I ask you,
what do you think
big George is gonna feel about little George
seeing no evil, hearing no evil?
Well, we're not gonna tell our parents.
We're just gonna keep it between ourselves.
Oh, George isn't gonna tell his father
about this thing!
Damn decent of him.
(EXCLAIMS)
- Scusi, Colonnello.
- Prego.
I love it when you hurt me.
Tell me now, Charlie.
This George Willis, Jr., what's his father do?
I don't really know.
Well, I'm gonna tell you.
When George Willis, Senior,
isn't busy as a million-dollar man
for Aetna Casualty É
Or is it New England distributor
for the Chrysler Corporation?
He concerns himself with
his young son, George Willis, Jr.
George isn't going to say anything
to his father.
Oh, Charlie.
Big George is gonna wind up little George,
and little George is gonna
sing like a canary.
And if you're hip, kid,
you're gonna hop to, too.
You've got this all figured out, don't you?
It don't take no Young American merit
scholarship to figure this one out.
Charlie, you had a little life,
so you decided to go to the Baird school
to put yourself in the market for a big one.
Now, in order to stay in the running,
you're gonna have to tell these people
what they want to know.
You think so?
Are we finished, Sofia?
- Yes.
- Grazie. Grazie. Andate.
Charlie,
if you don't sing now,
you're gonna end up,
not only shelving biscuits
in some convenience store
in the Oregon 'burbs,
but probably the last word
you'll ever hear yourself say
just before you croak, gonna be,
"Have a nice day and come back soon."
Sofia!
Measure up Charlie, here, pronto.
We got a date for Thanksgiving.
We got a date?
My brother's place.
W.R. Slade, White Plains, New York.
Colonel, I can't go with you
to your brother's place.
I mean, I should be getting back to school.
Well, you gotta have
Thanksgiving somewhere.
I mean, eats and treats.
I can use the company, Charlie.
All right.
Does he know I'm comin'?
He doesn't know I'm comin'.
But wait till you see the look on his face
when I walk through the door.
Oh, he loves me!
Oh, Charlie, about your little problem,
there are two kinds of people in this world:
those who stand up and face the music,
and those who run for cover.
Cover's better.
Okay, Sofia, suit him up!
Make him pretty.
Careful.
- Should I ring it?
- Yeah.
- Yes?
- Yes!
Who is this?
It's Randy.
Randy? You new?
I'm your nephew.
Hah! Here I am!
Your sister's been hoarding me
long enough.
Thought it's time
to spread the riches around.
- Uncle Frank.
- Gloria!
- Gail.
- Of course.
Say hello to the potluck party
from New York City.
Good old Uncle Frank
and this here with him is Charlie Simms,
star halfback of the Baird football team.
They not only beat Exeter and Groton,
but Aquinas High School, too.
Where's your miserable father?
Wait! No, no. Let's surprise him.
Give that fat heart of his an attack. Willie!
Ho, Willie!
Hello, Frank.
- How you doin'?
- Okay.
Here's my hand.
Charlie, meet W.R. Slade.
Nice to meet you, sir.
The original bulging briefcase man.
Gretchen, I smell those prunes!
- We talkin' turkey Marbella?
- Yes, we are.
(WHOOPS)
Let's have a whiff. Come on.
You know, I always had a sneaker for you.
Come here.
(SNIFFING)
(COUGHS)
(EXCLAIMS)
- Where are you, Garry? I heard you cough.
- GARRY: Right here.
Who are you again?
I'm here at the Waldorf with É
Is it your brother?
W.R.'s final issue. How ya doin', son?
Yeah, sure, Frank's my brother.
Who the hell are you?
I'm takin' care of him for the weekend.
Charlie.
Sorry.
Where's the booze?
Flowin' like mud here.
To tell the truth,
the Colonel's not well, I don't think.
Not well?
I think he's a little lonely.
Why didn't you take him
to your family's for dinner?
I heard that!
I heard that.
Pay no attention to him, Charlie.
That's just big-brother talk.
He's been watching out
for me since day one.
Bailed me out of more trouble
than he'd like to remember. Hmm?
GRETCHEN: Here, let me take your coat.
I meant to pick up some vino on my way up,
but I blew it.
I'll send you the Rothschild again
for Christmas,
only let's see how Thanksgiving goes.
I'll set two more places.
Here's your drink, Frank.
Oh, thank you, Randy.
Still with Snow Queen Sugar?
Snow Flake.
Why do you always get that wrong?
Because it's not important
for me to get it right.
What are you doing there now?
I'm vice president for marketing.
Hoo-ah! Congratulations!
Sugar is shit, though.
I told General Abrams,
install honey in the commissaries.
If K-50s didn't blow your brains out,
sugar, sure as shit, was gonna.
(FRANK LAUGHS)
Why don't we all sit down?
Ooh. (SNIFFING)
Mitsouki. Rhymes with nookie. Be careful.
When the wife gets restless,
the wife gets racy.
Well, let's go and eat, shall we?
By all means.
Thank you, Charlie.
Where you wanna sit, Frank?
At the head again?
Any old card table will do. This is fine.
Where was I? Oh.
So, I wake up. It's 4:00 in the morning.
I don't know who I'm with
or why I'm there, or where I am.
What am I gonna do? I got this Asian flower
on one hand, all giggly and dewy-like,
and this hard-boiled Navy nurse
outta Omaha, on the other.
We're three across the bed,
not a stitch of clothes on.
It comes to me.
Let east meet west.
We'll build a golden bridge.
(FRANK CHUCKLES)
I felt like I'd just joined
the corps of engineers!
We all still here?
It's a beautiful story.
Do you always enjoy
shocking people, Uncle Frank?
Honey É
I didn't know
you were so easily shocked, Randy.
I admire your sensibilities, I'm touched.
Dad, remember the time
you persuaded Frank
to go to the kennel?
What about it?
He almost put the seeing eye dog business
outta business.
Cool it, Randy.
It's over and done with.
FRANK: Indeed it is, Garry.
Indeed it is. So is dinner.
Charlie, what time you have?
I think we better be gettin' back.
You ever given any thought to
a Braille watch, Frank?
Randy É
Stevie Wonder wears one,
or do you rank on him, too?
Honey, please.
It's all right, Gloria.
I enjoy Randy's observations.
My wife's name is Gail, Frank.
Can you hear that? Gail.
Excuse me. Gail.
Gail strikes me as a very beautiful woman,
but, you know,
there's a little tension in her voice.
I don't know what it is.
It could be one of two things,
either Gail is nervous or unsatisfied.
What's your point, Uncle Frank?
You ought to go down on her.
- (CLINKS)
- Cut it out, Frank, will ya?
You've gotten so wrapped up in sugar,
you forgotten the taste of real honey!
Frank, for God's sake!
Hear that voice?
There's fire under that dress.
- Will you cut it out?
- Just get the fuck outta here.
- Hoo-ah!
- RANDY: Get in your limousine.
Go down to the Bowery. Get with
the other fucking drunks, where you belong!
Wait a minute.
- What?
- Can you take it easy?
RANDY: What for?
You want me to lay off him, Chucky,
'cause he's blind?
No, but É
My friend's name is Charles.
He doesn't like to be called Chucky.
This is supposed to be
a family get-together.
Just a warning.
Jesus Christ, another sucker who thinks
this shit-heel's a war hero.
Hoo-ah!
Well, once, maybe.
I suppose he told you about his days
on Lyndon Johnson's staff?
I was gonna go. Now I'm not leaving. Hah!
Frank was earmarked for general.
Earmarked, good word.
Frank likes to spit in everybody's eye!
Randy, that's enough.
So they, what do they call it,
when they give you the shaft in the military?
Passed over!
Right, Frank was passed over for promotion.
Couple times.
You wanna know what happened then?
Will you shut your mouth?
He blew himself up.
Stop it, Randy.
Our Colonel here had a grenade juggling act
at Fort Bragg, or wherever
it was they dumped him.
Fort Benning.
He was teaching hand-to-hand combat
to second lieutenants É
Randy, look at me
when you're talking to me, now, son.
I'm lookin', Frank.
His partner in the act was some captain.
Major Vincent Squires.
RANDY: Whoever he was.
Before going on,
they'd have a lo-cal breakfast,
a screwdriver for Frank,
bloody mary for his partner.
No, Vincent drank Sea Breezes.
The Judge Advocate at Benning said
Colonel Slade had four to his partner's one.
He's really flying in class.
He gets all excited.
He starts pulling the pins out.
One grenade got away from him.
Boom.
The one that got away.
RANDY: The pin was in, Frank claims.
In or out, what difference does it make?
What kind of fucking lunatic
juggles grenades?
Vinnie came out okay.
All Frank lost was his eyesight.
You wanna know the truth?
Got a handle on that, do you?
He was an asshole before.
Hoo-ah!
Now all he is, is a blind asshole.
Hoo-ah.
Hey, God's a funny guy.
God doth have a sense of humor.
Maybe God thinks
some people don't deserve to see.
(FAINTLY) Hoo-ah.
(EXCLAIMS)
You get the point, Chucky?
(GROANS)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
His name is Charles.
You can say that, can't you? Charles.
Know what this is, Randy?
It's a Ranger choke hold.
- From teaching those lieutenants.
- Colonel, let go.
Little pressure, I bust your windpipe.
- CHARLIE: I don't care what he said to me.
- After me.
Charles.
Just let go, please!
(CHOKING)
Gretchen?
You outdid yourself.
If you twist my arm hard enough,
we're talking turkey Marbella next year.
Who knows?
Frank?
Goodbye, Willie.
I'm no fucking good.
And I never have been.
Come on, Charlie, get the coats.
Colonel. Watch your step.
Hold it.
(SIGHS)
Nueva York, compadre. Vamos!
(METALLIC CLINKING)
You got a watch?
It's 7:20.
I didn't ask you the time.
I asked if you had a watch.
Yeah, in the other room.
Get it.
Colonel, there's a clock
right next to your bed.
Does it have a second hand?
- Yeah.
- Time me!
How long?
About 30 seconds.
I'm rusty.
Where did you get a gun, Colonel?
Piece or weapon, Charlie, never gun.
Where did you get the piece?
I'm an officer in the US Army.
This is my sidearm.
But you're not an officer anymore.
So I'm retired, so what?
An officer never relinquishes his .45.
You better relinquish it to me
or I'm gonna have to call Mrs. Rossi.
Good idea.
Then I'm going back to school.
Even better. Blue skies, green lights.
I hope you have a wonderful trip.
That felt like 25.
Gotta be able to do a .45 in 25.
Did you time me?
I did not and I'm calling Albany.
That was stupid.
Was it?
You're stuck with me, Charlie.
No, I'm not. I'm outta here!
Where you going, New Hampshire?
You got no money. How you gonna do that?
Mmm.
Karen's number tastes like Albany.
Hah!
Fine. I'm leaving.
Charlie. Charlie!
All I want from you is another day.
For what?
One last tour of the battlefield.
I can get around a city like New York,
but I
sometimes need a point
in the right direction.
What do you say, Charles?
What's one day between friends?
All right. Say I stay for another day.
Will you give me your weapon?
Oh, Charlie,
I'm a lieutenant colonel, United States Army.
I'm not giving my fucking gun to anyone.
Now, what are you drinkin'?
Colonel, this is unacceptable.
Unacceptable? What are you givin' me
that prep school crap for?
Unacceptable?
What have they done,
taken the Oregon out of the boy?
Put in Harvard Business School?
Then give me your bullets.
You do see the sense of it, Charlie,
don't you?
I can't chew the leather anymore.
So, why should I share
the tribe's provisions?
I mean, there's no one
wants to tear a herring with me anymore.
The bullets, Colonel.
"The bullets, Colonel."
You sound like a guy in
Lives of a Bengal Lancer.
What do you give a shit for?
About what?
About whether I blow my brains out or not.
Because I have a conscience.
You have a conscience.
I forgot.
The Charlie Conscience.
Do we tell? Do we not tell?
Do we follow the rich boy's code or not?
Do we let this blind asshole
die or not?
Yeah.
Conscience, Charlie.
When were you born, son?
Around the time of the Round Table?
(SCOFFS)
Haven't you heard?
Conscience is dead.
No, I haven't heard.
Then take the fucking wax outta your ears!
Grow up!
It's fuck your buddy.
Cheat on your wife.
Call your mother on Mother's Day.
Charlie,
it's all shit.
Where you goin'?
I got piss call.
I know I said I need ya for just one day
but even I can't hold it that long.
Oh, and Charlie,
you forgot the one in the chamber.
Hah!
There you go, sir.
Thank you.
Twenty-six years in the service,
never let an aide shine my shoes.
Where you gonna be in 26 years, Charlie?
Playing golf with your friends
from the Baird School, I bet.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
I don't even like those guys.
Of course you don't. They're all assholes.
Be a pleasure to squeal on 'em, wouldn't it?
Yeah, well, I'm not a squealer.
"I'm not a squealer."
What is this, the Dreyfus case?
Ooh. Ooh, mama!
BARBER: There you go.
Thank you.
BARBER: Thank you.
Watch your step.
I'm gettin' that heavy feelin' again, Charlie.
There's more to this, isn't there?
Isn't there?
I was offered a bribe.
Now we're cookin'.
Mr. Trask, the headmaster,
he promised to get me into Harvard.
If you squeal.
Yeah.
What a dilemma.
Should Charlie Simms accept a free ride
into Harvard, or not?
What do you think your friend George
would do if he were in your shoes?
He is, practically.
How?
It's just that Mr. Trask hasn't promised
to get him into Harvard.
Mr. Trask doesn't have to.
George's father's gonna take care of that.
Do the deal, Charlie. Take it!
Go to Harvard.
I can't do that.
Why not?
There are just some things you can't do.
Explain 'em to me.
Louder, please.
I can't É
You're gonna have a tough time
in this world, Charlie.
To ease the blow,
let me buy you a drink. Come on.
FRANK: Double Jack Daniels on the rocks.
And bring my young friend here
a Shirley Temple.
Hold on. Do you have beer?
Certainly. May I see some ID?
Are you interested in walkin'
the rest of your life, chappy?
I'm sorry, sir, but É
I'm a regular here. My boy's going on 23.
Why don't you call up front, the office?
Mr. Gilbert, he's a friend of mine.
(ORCHESTRA PLAYING)
Any particular beer?
Schlitz. No Schlitz?
Blatz. No Blatz?
Improvise.
I'll do my best, sir.
Thank you, sir.
You're human, Charlie. Beer?
Who are we drinking with?
I'm getting a nice soap-and-water feeling
from down there.
A female.
"Female"?
You callin' her female must mean
you like her or you wouldn't be so casual.
(CHUCKLES)
Is she alone?
Yeah, she's alone.
Things are heatin' up.
Chestnut hair?
Brown, light brown.
Twenty-two?
What am I, a guy at a carnival?
The day we stop lookin', Charlie,
is the day we die.
Move.
- Where?
- You know where, son.
Don't be coy, Charlie.
This woman is made for you. I can feel it.
Goddamn beautiful, isn't she?
- She's not bad.
- Bingo! The boy's alive.
Come on, son, perambulate.
Perambulate.
Excuse me, se–orita,
do you mind if we join you?
I'm feelin' you're being neglected.
I'm expecting somebody.
Instantly?
No, but any minute now.
Any minute?
Some people live a lifetime in a minute.
What are you doin' right now?
I'm waiting for him.
Would you mind if we waited with you,
just to keep the womanizers
from bothering you?
No, I don't mind.
Thank you.
Charlie.
You know, I detect a fragrance in the air.
Don't tell me what it is.
Ogilvie Sisters soap.
That's amazing.
I'm in the amazing business.
It is Ogilvie Sisters soap.
My grandmother gave me
three bars for Christmas.
Oh! I'm crazy about your grandmother.
I think she'd have liked Charlie, too.
Don't pay any attention to him.
What's your name?
Donna.
Donna? I'm Frank. This here is É
Charlie.
Yes. She likes you.
Charlie's having a difficult weekend.
He's going through a crisis.
How does he look like he's holding up?
He looks fine to me.
Oh! She does like you, Charlie.
So, Donna,
do you tango?
No. I wanted to learn once, but É
But?
But Michael didn't want to.
Michael.
The one you're waiting for.
Michael thinks the tango's hysterical.
I think Michael's hysterical.
Don't pay any attention to him.
Did I already say that?
(LAUGHING)
What a beautiful laugh.
Thank you, Frank.
Would you like to learn to tango, Donna?
Right now?
I'm offering you my services, free of charge.
What do you say?
I think I'd be a little afraid.
Of what?
Afraid of making a mistake.
No mistakes in the tango, Donna.
Not like life.
It's simple.
That's what makes the tango so great.
If you make a mistake,
get all tangled up, just tango on.
Why don't you try?
Will you try it?
All right. I'll give it a try.
Hold me down, son.
Your arm?
Charlie,
I'm gonna need some coordinates here, son.
The floor's about 20 by 30,
and you're at the long end.
There's some tables on the outside
and the band's on the right.
(LIGHT TANGO MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC INTENSIFIES)
(EXCLAIMS)
(LAUGHING)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(PEOPLE APPLAUDING)
Oh, Frank, you are one incredible dancer.
Wait'll you see Charlie dance.
He's a liar. I don't dance.
Isn't he a charmer, though?
Truth is, not only can he dance,
but he'll sing you a hell of a tune.
He can do bird calls
and imitate Bela Lugosi.
Hi, honey.
- Hi.
- Hey.
Michael, this is Frank and this is Charlie.
Hi, Frank, Charlie. Sorry I'm late.
Oh, that's okay.
These two gentlemen entertained me,
and time flew.
Your girl is a hell of a tango dancer.
At last, you found someone to tango with.
That's terrific!
Let me shake your hand.
No, it was Frank.
Hell, I'll shake both your hands!
This looks like the place, but we gotta go.
We got a date with Darryl and Carol
in the Village.
- Do you have a check?
- Michael, please.
My pleasure.
Oh, no, no. I got this.
Michael, get your hand outta your pocket.
I'll take it. Really.
Allow me.
Why, thank you.
Bye, guys.
Bye.
Darryl and Carol. Yeah.
MANNY: It's apartment 17E, Colonel.
She's expecting you.
Don't worry about a thing.
She's the crème de la crème.
My buddy took
the Vice Chancellor of Germany to her.
Now he wants to immigrate to this country.
FRANK: You did good, hombre.
My hair, how is it?
It's perfect.
I got the red foulard okay, didn't I?
Yeah, real dark red.
Burgundy, Charlie. Burgundy. They love it.
Bay rum.
Windsor knot.
That's my heart I'm feelin'.
I'm off.
Can you get long distance on this?
And how. Be my guest.
(DIALING)
WOMAN: Sugarbush Lodge.
Hi. George Willis, please?
One moment, please.
- HARRY: Hello?
- Harry?
Chas, how are you?
You just caught us. We're about to shoot
George over to the airport.
Why is George going to the airport?
Hold on.
Maybe you should talk to the man himself.
GEORGE: Chas.
Yeah. Hi, George.
You just caught me.
That's what Harry said. Where you goin'?
Home.
To Boston?
Catching the puddle-jumper.
Keep your fingers crossed.
What are you going home for?
(GEORGE SIGHS)
I was thinking. This asshole, Trask?
He's making no sense at all.
Somebody's gotta talk to him.
My father was class of '59.
Your father? I thought we were gonna
keep our parents outta this.
This guy Trask is out of control, Chas.
Out of control!
Somebody's gotta talk to him.
My father's a major fundraiser, you know.
No, I didn't.
(LAUGHING) Right.
Relax. He'll get us off the hook.
I gotta go. Everything all right?
Sure.
I'll see you Monday. Goodbye.
Bye.
(SIGHS)
- Good night, sir.
- Good night.
Hiya, Charlie.
Watch the door.
What a beautiful woman.
Hello, there.
MAN 1 ON TV: Do you see what I see?
MAN 2 ON TV: Yeah.
Either there's something wrong,
or we got the world's worst hangover.
HERMAN MUNSTER ON TV:
Won't you come in?
MAN 1 ON TV: We hear you got a picture
of the bank robbery.
(SWITCHES OFF TV)
Colonel?
Colonel, you all right?
What is it?
It's after noon.
You've been sleeping all morning.
So what?
I don't know. I thought É
I talked to George last night.
His father's a big-deal alumnus at school.
He's got a lot of pull.
Really?
Yeah, he's gonna talk to the headmaster.
George thinks he might be able
to get us off the hook.
"Get us off the hook."
Yeah, that's what he said.
Watch the "us" part.
Colonel, don't you wanna
get up and do something?
Colonel?
Oh, Charlie, what do you want?
I don't know,
but you're making me nervous.
My wallet is on the dresser.
Take out your plane ticket
and $400 mustering-out pay, plus
airport-to-school taxi.
Colonel, it's no rush. I mean, I can É
I could stay for a while.
Charlie, you already gave me a day.
And for that day, I am eternally grateful.
But right now I have other plans.
What other plans do you have?
To die, son.
Colonel, you're É
Come on, Colonel,
you're not gonna die today.
Charlie, give me your hand.
You go now, boy. Okay?
You go. Just É
Just leave me sleep here.
Look É Can we start over, please?
What do you feel like doin' today, huh?
Look at this. The sun is shining!
It's a beautiful day. Let's É
Colonel, I know
you don't want to be a party poop,
so let's go out and do something.
Let's go for a ride.
Yeah, a ride.
A ride?
Yeah, Colonel Slade, what do you say?
Let's go for a ride, huh?
What kind of ride?
Yeah, this is a valid Oregon driver's license,
and we let appropriate customers
test-drive the Testarossa.
But you're 17, with a blind companion.
That we don't do.
This is a $190,000 piece of machinery.
I'm not letting it out this door.
How about this one over here?
That's a Cabriolet T. The same deal.
You think I'll let an unaccompanied kid
get in a $110,000 car?
He will not be unaccompanied.
I'll be with him. I'm his father.
You're his father?
Yes.
I have an idea.
Why don't I take your father for a test drive?
What's your quota, Freddie?
Don't worry about my quota. I do well.
How many Ferraris you sold this month?
That's not relevant to this discussion.
Freddie, the '80s are over.
Are you tryin' to tell me
these things are walkin' outta the store?
This is a Ferrari, sir, the finest machinery
made in the automobile industry.
If you like it that much, why don't you
sleep with it? Why are you sellin' it?
I'd love to accommodate you É
If this car performs the way I expect it to,
you will get a check of $101,000,
and change,
when you come in here tomorrow morning.
It's $109,000, plus $950, plus tax.
Freddie, for you
107 all in,
plus a case of champagne
to go with your leftover turkey.
What do you say?
Don't worry about the boy.
He drives so smooth,
you can boil an egg on the engine.
When we bring the car back,
I'll peel the egg for ya.
Listen, you made me laugh,
but I can't let the car go out.
Want a deposit?
This is not an installment item, sir.
Freddie, you're no spring chicken.
You know what they call me
at the home office?
"The Grey Ghost."
You know why they still keep me around?
There's no kid here
that can move a Ferrari like I can.
I'm known from coast to coast
like butter and toast.
Ask anybody about Freddie Bisco.
When I get a Ferrari É
Out the door!
(CHUCKLES)
You just made me laugh, Freddie.
Yeah?
2,000.
Unless you take it,
you're gonna make me cry.
I'm a grey ghost, too.
See? This is fun, isn't it?
(ENGINE STALLING)
(GEARS CLICKING)
Drop her into neutral. Slide her into second.
Pop the clutch.
(ENGINE REVS)
Straight. Hold it right like that.
Feel it? That's straight.
It's a straight street, so keep it straight.
CHARLIE: Keep it straight.
FRANK: No fun just to keep it straight.
You've got to move a little bit, feel the road.
Please? Just like this.
All right? There you go.
Take it nice and easy.
Do you like this?
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
Slow it down a little, Colonel.
You're goin' a little fast.
Colonel, slow it down.
Something's happened to my foot!
Slow it down, please.
Hold on. I think I've got another gear.
Colonel Slade?
Hoo-ah!
Watch out!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(CHUCKLES)
You'll get us killed!
Don't blame me, Charlie, I can't see!
Colonel, slow it down!
(LAUGHING)
Oh, Jesus!
Now let's see how this baby corners.
Corners?
Yeah. Say when.
Say when what?
Say when to turn.
Colonel, you can't turn the car.
Where's the turn, Charlie?
3 o'clock? 2 o'clock?
Right oblique? Right face?
Come on! Talk to me!
It's left, I guess.
Left. I knew it. Okay. Now?
No, no! Not now! Not now!
Now?
Colonel, please!
I'm gonna do it anyway, all right?
Whether you say so or not, here we go!
Okay! Wait, wait, wait! Just wait!
Here I go.
Wait É Now!
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
I did it! Oh, Charlie!
(EXCLAIMING)
You're ridin' with one very happy man!
Turn again!
Be specific, son.
Left now!
Okay.
(YELLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
I love this! I love it!
Shall we take it to the max?
Let me out.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
Shit! The yellow flag.
I haven't even opened her up yet.
Which way's the curb?
Pull over. Slow down! Slow down.
I'm doin' it.
Pull over to the curb, here. Slow down.
Yep. Got it.
Ooh. Haven't had a ticket in years.
I'll do the talking.
License and registration.
Are you test-driving this baby?
Don't she purr, though?
At 70 miles an hour?
You should hear her at 125.
(CHUCKLES)
Where's your license?
At the dealer's.
They give it back when you return the car.
You got ID?
You bet.
Indeed.
Lieutenant Colonel Slade.
And you, soldier?
The name is Police Officer Gore.
Doin' a hell of a job, Gore.
And so are you, Colonel.
Who's the kid?
My boy Charlie.
He kept tellin' me to "let her out."
What was I gonna do, disappoint him?
Yes.
Tell you what I'm gonna do, Colonel.
I'm gonna let you go, on one condition.
What's that?
That you take this rig
straight back to the dealer.
You got it.
Shut up.
You want this?
Sure.
Gore?
Your face and your voice are familiar.
You ever been in
the officer's club at Da Nang?
No.
Never in the Army?
No. Coast Guard.
Good Lord.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHS)
Your dad is looking good, Charlie.
He's got a heavy foot, though.
Tell him to take it light, all right?
- I hear ya!
- All right.
Thanks.
Get out of the car,
because you are not driving anymore.
Just keeping this baby warm, that's all.
I'm not drivin' anymore.
Yes.
- Take my arm.
- I'm okay.
Colonel, it's really bumpy here.
You all right?
Yeah.
Red light. Hold it.
Taking too long.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(HORNS HONKING)
Shit! Colonel! Colonel!
Colonel!
Shit! You all right?
What the hell are you doing?
Take the cane.
I gotta take a piss.
Happens to the best of us.
We're on Park Avenue. You can't.
Perfect place.
You'll get arrested.
Never been housebroken. (EXCLAIMS)
Colonel! Shit!
What's the matter with you, Colonel?
What are you doing? Stand up.
Come on.
I'm tired, Charlie. I'm tired.
Give me your arm.
Here's your cane.
Take me back to the hotel, son.
Home at last.
You all right now?
Yeah.
Do you want to use the bathroom?
No.
Can I get you something?
You sure you're all right?
I'm fine, Charlie.
Do you mind if I use the phone?
Go ahead.
(DIALING)
MR. WILLIS: Hello?
Hi, is George there, please?
Senior or Junior?
Junior.
Who's this?
A friend of his from school.
Sorry, but George isn't going to be talking
to any friends from school right now.
Oh.
Goodbye.
Colonel, are you looking at me?
I'm blind, Charlie.
I'm gonna take a nap.
Too much fresh air.
It's probably a good idea.
Want me to help you to your room?
No.
Couch.
I like this couch here.
You sure you're all right, Colonel?
I got a headache.
(SIGHS)
Why don't you go downstairs,
get me some aspirin?
- Some aspirin.
- Yeah. Also É
I feel like a cigar.
Get me a couple of
Montecristos Number One.
Yeah.
You won't be able to get 'em
at the newsstand downstairs.
So why don't you go over to
50th and Fifth, Dunhill's.
Fella named Arnold there, in the humidor.
Tell him they're for me.
He'll know.
You're back too fast.
You didn't get my cigars, did you?
Get out of here, Charlie.
I thought we had a deal.
I welched. I'm a welcher. Didn't I tell you?
No, what you told me was
that you gave me all the bullets.
I lied.
You could have fooled me.
And I did.
How you ever gonna survive
in this world without me?
Why don't you just
give me the gun, all right?
(STUTTERING) What are you doing?
I'm gonna shoot you, too.
Your life's finished anyway.
Your friend George
is going to sing like a canary.
And so are you.
And once you've sung, Charlie, my boy,
you're gonna take your place
on that long, gray line
of American manhood.
And you will be through.
I'd like to disagree with you, Colonel.
You're in no position
to disagree with me, boy.
I got a loaded .45 here. You got pimples.
I'm gonna kill ya, Charlie,
because I can't bear the thought
of you sellin' out!
Put the gun down, all right, Colonel?
What? You givin' me an ultimatum?
No, I'm É
I give the ultimatums!
I'm sorry.
All right? I'm sorry.
It's all right,
Charlie.
You break my heart, son.
All my life I stood up
to everyone and everything,
because it made me feel important.
You do it 'cause you mean it.
You got integrity, Charlie.
I don't know whether
to shoot you or adopt you.
Not much of a choice, is it, sir?
Oh. Don't get cute now.
Could you please put the gun away?
I asked you a question.
Do you want me to adopt you, or don't you?
Please? I mean É
You're just in a slump right now.
Slump?
No slump, Charlie.
I'm bad.
I'm not bad. No.
I'm rotten.
You're not bad.
You're just in pain.
What do you know about pain?
You little snail darter
from the Pacific Northwest.
Fuck you know about pain?
Let me have the gun, Colonel.
No time to grow a dick, son.
Just give me the gun, all right, Colonel?
I'm talkin' a parade ground.
Ten-hut!
Soldier, that was a direct order.
Give me the gun.
You can stay or you can leave.
You understand?
Either way, I'm gonna do this thing.
Now why don't you leave
and spare yourself?
I want your gun, Colonel.
I'm gonna give myself a count.
You need a count for balance.
Five É
Four É
Three É
Two É
One É
Fuck it.
(GRUNTING)
Give me! Fuck!
Get out of here!
I'm stayin' right here!
Get outta here!
I'm stayin' right here.
I'll blow your fuckin' head off!
Then do it!
You want to do it? Do it! Let's go.
Get outta here!
You fucked up, all right? So what?
So everybody does it.
Get on with your life, would ya?
What life?
I got no life!
I'm in the dark here!
You understand?
I'm in the dark!
So give up.
You want to give up, give up.
Because I'm givin' up, too.
You said I'm through.
You're right, I am through.
We're both through. It's all over.
So let's get on with it. Let's fuckin' do it.
Let's fuckin' pull the trigger,
you miserable blind motherfucker.
Pull the trigger.
Here we go, Charlie.
I'm ready.
You don't want to die.
And neither do you.
Give me one reason not to.
I'll give you two.
You can dance the tango and drive a Ferrari
better than anyone I've ever seen.
You never seen anyone do either.
Give me the gun, Colonel.
Oh, where do I go from here, Charlie?
If you're tangled up, just tango on.
You askin' me to dance, Charlie?
(SINGING) Did you ever have the feelin'
That you wanted to go
And still had the feelin'
that you wanted to stay?
You like my blues, Charlie?
Yeah, they're beautiful.
I wore these
for Lyndon's inauguration.
Of course, we weren't the number one ball.
But he dropped by anyway.
Will you please give me the gun?
You're askin' an officer
to surrender his sidearm.
You don't have to surrender it.
Just put it down for a little while.
All right? Just put it down.
Boy, I could use a drink, Charlie.
How about a cup of coffee?
(SCOFFS)
Too big a leap for me right now, Charlie.
Maybe tomorrow.
(LAUGHS)
No, a Mr. John Daniels would be preferred.
No water, Charlie.
No water.
Please.
Here's your drink, Colonel.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
What time do you want me
to turn down the bed?
Maybe later, all right?
What he means, se–orita,
is come right in.
Later, please?
Yes, sir. Good afternoon.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Nice voice.
(LAUGHS)
Boy, you have a one-track mind.
Is there anything else in this world, Charlie?
Not for you.
You know what's kept me goin'
all these years?
The thought
that one day É
Never mind.
The what?
Silly.
Just the thought that maybe one day, I'd É
I could have a woman's arms
wrapped around me,
and her legs wrapped around me.
And what?
That I could wake up in the morning
and she'd still be there.
Smell of her.
All funky and warm.
I finally gave up on it.
I don't know why you can't have that.
When we get back to New Hampshire,
I don't know why you can't find someone.
You're a good-lookin' guy
and you're fun to be with
and you're a great travel companion,
sensitive, compassionate.
Charlie,
are you fuckin' with me?
(LAUGHS)
Yes.
(PHONE RINGING)
Yeah?
Hey, Manny.
(STAMMERING)
We missed our plane.
Your plane, Charlie.
My ticket was one-way.
New England Thruway all the way, Colonel?
All the way, Manolo.
I'm gettin' that heavy feelin' again, Charlie.
Uh É
"Uh É"
I think you were right
about George and his father.
I'm sorry to hear that.
When we get back Mr. Trask is bringing us
up in front of the whole school.
Puttin' your feet to the fire?
Special meeting of
the disciplinary committee.
And what are you gonna tell 'em?
I don't know. I'll think of somethin'.
Charlie, why are you all alone in this thing?
Hmm?
Where's your father?
He left.
I thought it was a mom-and-pop store.
Who's the pop?
It's my stepfather.
Oh, yeah.
But why isn't he in on this?
Somethin' wrong with him?
No, he's okay. We just É
We don't get along very well.
Why not?
Because he's an asshole.
(EXCLAIMS)
(CHUCKLES)
Well, that's all right, Charlie.
Every family's got one nowadays.
That's it?
That's it.
Take care of yourself, kid.
All right, Manny. Thanks.
FRANK: No, I'm not opening.
I hate goodbyes.
So É
You'll be all right, huh?
I'll be fine.
All right.
(BELL TOLLING)
What's that?
That's first bell.
Just got time to get cleaned up.
Oh.
I almost forgot.
I owe you some money.
$300. Job well done.
You ever need any references, Charlie,
I'm your man.
Thanks, Colonel.
16 Water Street. Over the bridge.
We'll find it.
Goodbye, Charlie.
Goodbye, Colonel.
Come here, son.
Okay, Manny.
(BOYS CHATTERING)
George. George!
(BOYS SHUSHING)
I called an open meeting
of this institution this morning
because the incident
that occurred this Tuesday last
describes an issue that concerns all of us.
Not an isolated case of vandalism.
What happened is a symptom
of the sickness of a society.
A sickness which runs counter to
the principles this school was founded on.
A school among whose graduates
two have sat behind the desk
in the Oval Office, in the White House.
Baird men have run State Departments
and investment houses,
founded department stores
and coached football teams.
Our alumni receive their bulletins
in ashrams in India
and in palaces in Jordan.
We are, in fact, known around the world
as the cradle of this country's leadership.
- A beacon in the É
- What are you doing here?
Got room for me up there, Charlie?
But today we are bleeding from disrespect.
Yeah, I guess so.
- Blatant disrespect.
- Give us a hand.
A disrespect for our values,
and a disrespect for our standards.
A disrespect for the Baird tradition.
And, as the custodians of that tradition,
we are here today to protect each other
from those who threaten it.
Who is this, Mr. Simms?
This is Mr. Frank Slade,
Lieutenant Colonel,
United States Army, retired.
I'm here in place of Charlie's parents.
Excuse me?
In loco parentis.
They could not make the trip
from Oregon today.
And what is your relationship to Mr. Simms?
Is this a courtroom?
Closest thing we could manage to it.
Then if we're taking oaths,
there's a few people I'd like to swear in.
There are no oaths at Baird.
We are all on our honor.
Larry and Franny Simms are
very dear, close friends of mine.
They've asked me to appear here
on Charlie's behalf.
Okay?
Happy to have you with us, Colonel.
Mr. Willis.
Which Mr. Willis?
George, Junior, sir.
Yes.
You were in a position last Tuesday night
to see who committed this act of vandalism.
Who was it?
Well, I have an idea who it was.
No, not an idea, Mr. Willis.
Did you see or did you not see?
Well É
I didn't have my contacts in.
Come on.
I was in the library. I'd taken my glasses off,
and I was gonna put my contacts back in.
Then I helped Simms close up
and the next thing I know, we're outside,
and I hear this sound and I
didn't have any time to put my contacts in.
Whom, with your limited vision,
did you see?
(WHISPERING)
Like I say, it was blurry.
I can't see without my contacts.
What did you see, Mr. Willis?
What?
You mean definitively?
Stop fencing with me, Mr. Willis!
Tell me what you saw!
Now, don't hold me to this,
but no contacts, it's dark É
And everything, I mean É
Mr. Willis!
Maybe É
Harry Havemeyer,
Trent Potter and Jimmy Jameson.
(BOYS MUTTERING)
Maybe?
Ballpark, best guess.
Could you provide us with some detail?
Why don't you ask Charlie?
I really think he was closer.
Mr. Simms.
(CLEARS THROAT) Yes.
You don't wear contact lenses, do you?
No, sir.
With your untrammeled sight,
whom did you see?
Well, I saw something,
but I couldn't say who.
All right. What was the something you saw?
I couldn't say.
You couldn't or wouldn't say?
Well, I just É
I just couldn't say.
Couldn't, wouldn't, shouldn't.
You're exhausting my patience
and making a mockery of these proceedings.
I will give you one last chance.
The consequences of your response
will be dire.
By dire, I mean your future will be
jeopardized permanently.
Now for the last time,
what did you see last Tuesday night
outside my office?
I saw somebody.
"I saw somebody." Good.
Did you see their size and shape?
Yeah.
And they were the size and shape of whom?
They were the size and shape
of most any Baird student, sir.
I am left with no real witness.
Mr. Willis' testimony is not only vague,
it is unsubstantiated.
The substance I was looking for, Mr. Simms,
was to come from you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, too, Mr. Simms,
because you know what I'm going to do
inasmuch as I can't punish Mr. Havemeyer,
Mr. Potter or Mr. Jameson?
And I won't punish Mr. Willis.
He's the only party to this incident
who is still worthy
of calling himself a Baird man.
I'm going to recommend to
the disciplinary committee
that you be expelled.
Mr. Simms, you are a cover-up artist
and you are a liar.
But not a snitch!
Excuse me?
No, I don't think I will.
Mr. Slade.
This is such a crock of shit!
Please watch your language, Mr. Slade.
You are in the Baird school, not a barracks.
Mr. Simms, I will give you
one final opportunity to speak up.
Mr. Simms doesn't want it.
He doesn't need to be labeled
"still worthy of being a Baird man."
What the hell is that?
What is your motto here?
"Boys, inform on your classmates,
save your hide,
"anything short of that,
we're gonna burn you at the stake?"
Well, gentlemen,
when the shit hits the fan, some guys run,
and some guys stay.
Here's Charlie, facin' the fire,
and there's George,
hidin' in big daddy's pocket.
And what are you doin'?
You're gonna reward George
and destroy Charlie.
Are you finished, Mr. Slade?
No, I'm just gettin' warmed up.
I don't know who went to this place.
William Howard Taft,
William Jennings Bryan,
William Tell, whoever.
Their spirit is dead, if they ever had one.
It's gone.
You're buildin' a rat ship here,
a vessel for seagoin' snitches.
And if you think you're preparin' these
minnows for manhood,
you better think again,
because I say you are killin' the very spirit
this institution proclaims it instills.
What a sham.
What kind of a show
are you guys puttin' on here today?
The only class in this act
is sittin' next to me.
And I'm here to tell you
this boy's soul is intact.
It's non-negotiable. You know how I know?
Someone here, and I won't say who,
offered to buy it.
Only Charlie here wasn't sellin'.
Sir, you're out of order.
I'd show you out of order.
You don't know what
out of order is, Mr. Trask.
I'd show you, but I'm too old,
I'm too tired, I'm too fuckin' blind.
If I were the man I was five years ago,
I'd take a flamethrower to this place!
Out of order?
Who the hell you think you're talkin' to?
I've been around, you know?
There was a time I could see.
And I have seen.
Boys like these, younger than these,
their arms torn out, their legs ripped off.
But there is nothin' like the sight
of an amputated spirit.
There is no prosthetic for that.
You think you're merely
sendin' this splendid foot soldier
back home to Oregon
with his tail between his legs,
but I say you are executin' his soul!
And why?
Because he's not a Baird man.
Baird men. You hurt this boy,
you're gonna be Baird bums, the lot of you.
And, Harry, Jimmy,
Trent, wherever you are out there,
fuck you, too!
(BOYS MUTTERING)
(GAVEL BANGING)
Stand down, Mr. Slade!
I'm not finished.
As I came in here, I heard those words,
"cradle of leadership."
Well, "when the bough breaks,
the cradle will fall," and it has fallen here.
It has fallen.
Makers of men, creators of leaders.
Be careful what kind of leaders
you're producin' here.
I don't know if Charlie's silence
here today is right or wrong.
I'm not a judge or jury.
But I can tell you this,
he won't sell anybody out to buy his future!
And that, my friends, is called integrity.
That's called courage.
Now that's the stuff
leaders should be made of.
Now I have come to
the crossroads in my life.
I always knew what the right path was.
Without exception, I knew,
but I never took it.
You know why?
It was too damn hard.
Now here's Charlie.
He's come to the crossroads.
He has chosen a path. It's the right path.
It's a path made of principle
that leads to character.
Let him continue on his journey.
You hold this boy's future
in your hands, committee.
It's a valuable future, believe me.
Don't destroy it. Protect it.
Embrace it.
It's gonna make you proud one day,
I promise you.
How's that for cornball?
Nothing can shut them up, sir.
(SILENCE)
The disciplinary committee will take
this matter under advisement
in closed session.
(MURMURING)
What are they doin', Charlie?
I think they're going to
come to a decision now.
Very well.
Apparently, that meeting
will be unnecessary.
Mrs. Hunsaker.
The joint student-faculty disciplinary
committee needs no further sessions.
They have come to a decision.
Messrs. Havemeyer, Potter and Jameson
are placed on probation
for suspicion of ungentlemanly conduct.
It is further recommended
that Mr. George Willis, Jr.
receive neither recognition
nor commendation
for his cooperation.
Mr. Charles Simms is excused
from any further response to this incident.
Hoo-ah!
(ALL CHEERING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(EXCLAIMS)
Last step.
I can always count on you, Charlie.
MISS DOWNES: Colonel!
I'm Christine Downes, Colonel Slade.
I teach political science.
I wanted to tell you how much I appreciate
you speaking your mind.
Why, thank you. Are you married?
(LAUGHS)
I É
Went to an artillery school
at Fort Sill with a Mickey Downes.
Thought he might've snagged you.
No, I'm afraid not.
Colonel Slade was on
Lyndon Johnson's staff, Miss Downes.
Were you? Fascinating.
We should get together,
talk politics sometime.
Fleurs de Rocaille.
Yes.
"Flowers from a brook."
That's right.
Well, Miss Downes,
I'll know where to find you.
Charlie.
CHARLIE: Bye, Miss Downes.
MISS DOWNES: Bye.
You don't have to tell me, Charlie.
5'7",
auburn hair,
beautiful brown eyes.
Yabba-dabba-doo.
Ha!
Manny.
Oh, Colonel, this is too much.
Never mind, you earned it.
Next time Charlie and I
want to take a breather to New York,
we're gonna call you.
You can drive us both ways.
You're on, Colonel.
Not only will it be an honor,
I'll give you a rate.
I'll see your rate and raise you.
Stay outta harm's way, Manny.
Take care, Colonel.
You, too.
- Ready?
- No. I'll take it from here.
You go on ahead.
Manny'll drive you to your dorm.
Come by before you go home for Christmas.
We'll have a little cheer.
And if you like, stay for dinner.
Sometimes she cooks a pot roast.
It's almost edible.
All right, Colonel. That'd be really É
Bye, Charlie.
Who's there? That you, Francine?
Yes.
What are you doing?
Taking a ride.
Taking a ride?
What about you giving me a lift?
No.
No?
Come on, Francine.
We should make up.
Don't you think it's time we made up?
No.
- Francine?
- What?
Uncle Frank's had
a really hard Thanksgiving weekend.
(KISSING)
What's that? I hear a chipmunk.
Is it a walrus?
No, it's Willie.
Willie, why don't you help me with my bag?
Come on, son. Help me with my bag.
Come on. Come on.
You got it. Hold onto it.
You're strong. Come on.
Here we are.
Francine, come on with me and Willie.
I'll let you make me
some marshmallow chocolate.
What do you say?
Good!