AUDREY WELLS: The book
Under the Tuscan Sun
was sent to me early in 2001
to see if I wanted to adapt it
into a screenplay.
And I was aware of the book.
I knew it had been a best-seller
for many months.
I read it and found that it had
real evocative power for me.
It was a memoir, really,
written by Frances Mayes
about buying a rundown villa
in Tuscany
and how the process of restoring it
sent her deep into Italian culture.
And it was a dense,
poetic piece of work
that was beautiful to read,
but contained nothing resembling
conventional screenplay structure.
At the time, however, l was
working on an idea of my own
about a woman
overcoming heartbreak.
And I started to realize that these
two stories could be combined.
That I could take the instigating
incident in Frances' book,
buying a villa in Tuscany,
getting a clean slate,
starting your life in a new way.
And I could combine that with the
elements that I had in my other story.
I met Frances Mayes in Tuscany
and she was well aware that
whoever was going to adapt her story
was going to have to bring
something big to the table.
She knew that someone
would need to bring plot,
and different characters,
and she was very, very open to that.
And I felt that she trusted me
to capture the essence of her book
in my screenplay adaptation,
because I felt that what the two
would eventually have in common
was that they would both
be internal adventure stories.
They would both be about resurrection,
in a sense,
and second chances in life.
It's true that this
is a pretty loose adaptation.
Most of the characters in the movie
don't exist in the book,
or are only suggested in the book.
And yet, despite the additions,
Frances Mayes ended up feeling
that the essence of her work
was well translated to the screen,
and I was very happy about that.
This first scene takes place
in a bookstore
in North Beach of San Francisco.
But in actual fact,
we built this set on a sound stage
at Cinecitta Studios in Rome.
For budgetary reasons,
it worked out better for us
to keep the same crew
and to build all the San Francisco
interiors in Rome.
It meant that I ended up
shooting in San Francisco,
my hometown, only one day.
But I feel that we created some
authenticity on those stages in Rome.
I think that bad reviews
should just be forgotten.
WELLS: lt was important
to me in this scene
to show Diane Lane's character,
Frances,
looking her very best, like a woman
in control, a happy woman.
And, ultimately, as we find out,
an unaware woman.
I just find that ironic.
Ironic? Why?
Ask your husband.
WELLS: One ofthe things
I looked forward to most
before I started making the movie
was the transition between
Diane's face here in this scene,
and the way she looks
when we see her in the next scene.
Here she is innocent.
She doesn't know yet.
And then, when we find her
in the next scene,
and we've leapt forward in time,
we quickly realize
that she knows much, much more
than she knew before.
The way she looks so ravaged in the
following scene is quite devastating.
MAN: Frances.
Frances?
I've got some unfortunate news for you.
WELLS: l wanted Diane Lane
for this part,
because I knew that I was going to be
making an overtly emotional movie.
And that can be a tricky thing to do,
and a risky thing to do.
There are a lot of pitfalls.
And its success lies entirely
on the actress.
And I knew that Diane would have
the authenticity and the bravery
in front of the camera
to carry that off for me.
And also that I could frame this serious
subject matter in a humorous way,
and that with Diane in the main part,
the audience would never lose touch
with the core pain of the character.
That no matter how light I got later on,
Diane would always ground the movie
with her performance.
We would never lose touch
with what we were really dealing with.
$200,000.
-I don't have that kind of money.
-Unfortunately, you do.
The house?
WELLS: This is Jeffrey Tambor
playing the attorney.
It's a tricky thing
trying to cast a really good actor
in a part that only plays one day.
Particularly when they have to fly
halfway across the world to do the role.
And I was really happy to get Jeffrey,
because I admire the way he layers his
performances with so much nuance.
He was very impressed with Diane
the day we filmed this scene,
and thought that we should just
keep him as an off-camera voice,
because why cut away from Diane
when she was being so riveting?
And if you let him have it, well,
you could end up
with a lot of money in your pocket.
I understand he wants it pretty badly.
Sorry. This is so surreal.
WELLS: Diane came in completely
prepared to film this scene.
She walked onto the set
looking pretty much
exactly as you see her here.
And we only filmed two takes.
This is take one
that I am using in the movie.
My experience with Diane is that she
rarely needed more than three takes
to achieve what we were looking for.
It's near the right schools.
Schools. She's...
Wow.
You're gonna get over this.
WELLS: Here when
Jeffrey Tambor says to her,
"You will get over this, Frances.
"You will.
Some day you will be happy again."
That's the kickoff for the movie,
because we look at that face
and we think,
"No, she will never be happy again."
And that, for me,
established the tension
and defined the road
that the movie was going to take.
He says,
"Someday you will be happy again."
We don't believe it.
But we are about to see it happen.
I thought it was important to show
the house that Frances lived in,
even though we never see
the ex-husband.
I felt that he would have
more creepy power
if I didn't identify him
with a particular actor playing the part.
I thought leaving him as a sinister ghost
was more powerful for the movie.
But I still wanted to see
what she was leaving behind.
Actually, that painting
that we placed behind her,
you can't really see the whole thing,
but it's a black specter
lurking behind her shoulder,
and I thought that
that represented the husband
on some subconscious way
that only l will ever (LAUGHlNG)
know about.
This action that Diane takes here
is something we came up
with in rehearsal that day.
And later I realized that the gesture
of taking flowers out of a vase
is repeated several times in the movie
by the old man who attends the shrine
outside Bramasole.
Here in this scene, it's a sort
of harbinger of things to come.
We always refer to this location
as the divorce hotel.
That's Jack Kehler, a terrific
character actor, playing the landlord.
The guy crying through the wall
is Matthew Labyorteaux.
He auditioned for me
over the phone in Los Angeles.
He called me up one evening
and sobbed over the telephone for me,
so I could get a feel
for what he would do
when we brought him
onto the looping stage.
Later I found out
that he had played Albert Ingalls
on Little House on the Prairie.
It's pretty amazing who you have
access to in Los Angeles.
-What do you do?
-I'm a writer.
So you can help the others
with their suicide notes.
Ah, you're one of those funny landlords.
Not really.
Well, here's your keys.
Have a good stay.
Thanks.
WELLS: We designed this room
to feel like purgatory,
a sort of way station for Frances.
And I had it filled with golf posters
to make it especially depressing.
Home.
WELLS: This San Francisco
restaurant interior
was actually shot inside a store
called Tod in the center of Rome.
Sandra Oh is the actress that plays
Frances' best friend, Patti.
I never considered another actress
for the part.
I knew Sandra
from my first film, Guinevere,
and I knew that she had
a unique, inimitable presence.
It's hard to express
what makes Sandra so special,
but it has something to do
with how she manages to project
gravity and levity simultaneously.
I decided to include
a lesbian couple in the movie,
because as I was working
on my theme about heartbreak,
I knew that if I didn't include
a lesbian couple,
I would only be featuring men
breaking women's hearts,
and I think heartbreak
is an equal opportunity killer.
-It changes our plans a little bit.
-Well, of course.
We were about to take a 1 0-day tour
to romantic Tuscany,
but I don't want Patti flying
during her first trimester.
Small sacrifice.
WELLS: When l watch this scene
I am reminded of many happy hours
in front of the Avid
with my editor, Andy Marcus.
A scene like this one, essentially,
it's three talking heads,
can be death without timing.
Andy always brought crispness
to the scenes,
and I think this kind of character-based
editing can be just as challenging
as cutting action scenes
that entail thousands of feet of footage.
No. Like that.
-That's your depression speaking.
-Well, it doesn't speak Italian.
It speaks a little high-school French.
Besides, I'm not depressed anymore.
Then what are you still doing living
at Camp Divorce with all those losers?
-Be nice. Those are my people.
-That's not a place you live.
Guys, come on.
Thank you so much.
There is no way that I can go
on a romantic tour of Tuscany
right now, okay?
-I mean, I'm not ready to meet anyone.
-Oh, you won't. That we can assure you.
Oh?
-It's a gay tour of romantic Tuscany.
-Oh.
So it would be very relaxing for you.
Mostly couples, no one would be there
to hit on you or check you out,
and you could just concentrate
and listen to your own inner voice.
My inner voice.
My inner voice that would be saying,
"What the fuck am I doing
on a gay tour of Tuscany?"
Frances, it's Italy. Italy.
Plus, you could use it
as a time to start writing.
Well, I'm busy.
I have to review all those books, Patti.
Instead of working on your own book.
WELLS: Post-production on this film,
meaning the picture and sound editing,
was a nonstop pleasure, really,
but production, the actual shoot in Italy
was a much more challenging story.
People have asked me,
with a lot of envy,
what it was like to spend
four months working in Italy.
But that's just the thing. We were
working. It wasn't exactly a vacation.
And there were cultural differences
that we all had to adjust to.
American movie crews
work a guaranteed 12 hours,
and frequently 14 hours,
and they'll work up to 17 hours,
if you make a deal with them
and they want the overtime.
Whereas, ltalian crews
work a 10-hour day
and one to two hours of that is lunch,
and they're really not interested
in earning the overtime.
They want to go home,
they want to watch the soccer game,
they want to participate in their
(CHUCKLING) real lives.
Which is easy to understand
from their point of view,
but difficult for a director
who is trying to accomplish a lot
and finish her scenes.
When I finally shot my one day
in San Francisco,
the day that you see here,
I shot a 17-hour day.
And it was the longest work day
that we'd ever had on the movie,
because we were working
with an American crew.
(SOBBING NEXT DOOR)
Hey!
-Sorry. Sorry.
-It's okay.
-You wanna come over?
-No!
(QUIETER SOBBING)
Maybe later.
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
"Maybe later." Oh...
WELLS: The composer on this movie
is Christophe Beck,
and l knew l wanted to work with him,
because we'd worked together
so successfully
on Guinevere, my first film.
And I'd enjoyed my time
with Chris so much
that I was looking forward
to doing it again.
We discussed what we wanted
the music to sound like for this film.
We divided it into three strands
that would become a single braid.
One sound would be
a fresh and modern sound,
like the one you hear right here,
that would be Frances' music.
Another sound for the movie
would be a more romantic, comedic,
classically Italian sound.
And the last thread
that we wanted to develop
would reference the great composer,
Nino Rota,
who scored all of Fellini's films.
-Now, Frances is straight...
-Aw...
...and she just survived
a terrible divorce,
and according to her friend Patti,
she really needs our support.
So, Frances, why don't you stand up
and let everyone say hello?
Come on, Frances, come on.
Hi.
Screw the bastard, Frances!
Have some fun!
WELLS: l didn't know that it was going
to rain on this day in Florence.
I was making a movie
called Under the Tuscan Sun,
and the weather was rather distressing.
But we decided to make the most of it,
and we got a bunch of red umbrellas.
And it ended up having
kind of a comedic feeling
that the weather was so bad
and stayed bad.
This begins the saga of our horrible
historically rainy fall in Tuscany.
When it wasn't raining, it was hazy,
and for a while there I was certain
I was going to be known as the woman
who made that ugly Tuscany movie.
Yes, she can.
Frances, a little more?
Thank you.
WELLS: These sunflowers l was
smart enough to get in pre-production
before we started shooting in the fall.
We shot these in July.
I was stiII in the United States,
and I'd just drawn some pictures
about what I wanted.
And this beautiful shot
we went back to get in May
after I convinced Disney
that I was the woman
making the ugly Tuscany movie.
We had some clear days in May
and some crystal clear horizons,
and I felt almost
religiously grateful for that.
The director of photography
that I chose to work with on this movie
is Geoffrey Simpson,
an Australian cinematographer,
who had so many beautiful-looking
movies to his credit.
We ended up
being great partners on this film,
and our approach to the movie
was to shoot in an almost touristic style
when Frances first gets to Italy
and is an outsider.
And then, to use the camera
in a more organic way,
when she has become quite literally
a part of the landscape.
I was very lucky to have Lindsay
Duncan in the role of Katherine,
and when I watch this scene
I remember how concerned
I was that day
about what the character would be
wearing the first time that we saw her.
I wanted her to look outrageous,
but not to seem so strange
that she took us out of the movie.
I remember being tortured this day
about whether or not she should
wear sunglasses and a hat,
orjust sunglasses, orjust a hat.
Those first impressions are
so important.
And I was very intent on creating
a believable character here,
despite her outrageousness.
We had two days
to shoot this sequence.
The marketplace
and the upcoming postcard montage.
But on the first day,
which started in full sun,
a sleet storm moved in at noon,
and the wind was incredible.
It knocked over all the lights
and tore the roofs off the food stalls.
So we had to wrap
and still finish the scene
in the amount of time originally allotted.
And that meant that I had to give up
on some fancy Steadicam stuff
that I had planned.
I used to be.
All right, well, have a go.
-To my mom.
-Dear Mom.
WELLS: Having Frances
write the postcard
was a way of getting into the text
of Frances Mayes' book.
A lot of what you are hearing here
comes from Frances' book, verbatim.
And it also established the voice-over
and allowed me to use it
later in the movie
in a way that would make us feel
that she was actually in the process
of writing her book
when she was speaking.
FRANCES: l eat a hot grape
from the market
and the violet sweetness
breaks open in my mouth.
It even smells purple.
I wish I could stay here longer,
but the bell of the campanile
reminds me of time.
"Ding-dang-dong," the bell says,
instead of "Ding-dong."
I wish you were here.
Love...
Rodney.
Thanks.
"Even smells like purple"? My mom will
never believe that I wrote this.
Keep it.
"'Ding-dang-dong,' goes the bell"!
WELLS: That was Dan's addition,
Dan Bucatinsky,
"Ding, dang, dong rang the bell."
He did that in the audition.
How can you resist that?
"Bramasole."
Bramasole. From "bramare,"
to yearn for, and "sole, " the sun.
WELLS: Casting Lindsay Duncan
was one of the best things
that happened on this movie.
She had just won the Tony
on Broadway
forherrole in Private Lives.
And my casting director, Linda Lowy,
thought that I should meet Lindsay.
We asked her to fly out to Los Angeles,
which she did on a Monday.
She flew out
and flew back on the same day,
because Mondays were dark
for her when she was on stage.
I don't even really remember
her reading for the part.
All I had to do was meet Lindsay
and feel her energy to know
that she would be perfect.
(CHATTER ON BUS)
WELLS: Sheep are not very good
at taking direction.
We spent an inordinate amount of time
trying to get that bus to roll up
and see the sheep.
It's not the kind of day
that you really enjoy,
because you know the sun
is going down
and we were over schedule
at the time that we shot this,
and had so many more places to go,
and more scenes to get.
Stop the bus.
-Stop the bus.
-What?
WELLS: So now we are
about to discover Bramasole.
And finding this location
was one of the toughest things
that we had to do in pre-production.
We were going to be
shooting in this house
more hours
than in any other location in the movie,
and we didn't have money
to build a set,
so we needed to use
a practical location.
And all the houses of that era
have small rooms and low ceilings,
meaning there is no place
to hide the lights,
and there's very little room
to maneuver.
We chose this house because
the ceilings were a little bit higher,
and it was fairly modest in scale,
which was important to me.
I didn't want Frances buying a palazzo
that none of us could ever imagine
coming close to.
Stephen McCabe,
my production designer,
really led the charge on this house.
He knew that he could make it work,
and he made it very beautiful
when it was completely unimpressive
and actually off-putting
when I first saw it.
(GASPS)
WELLS: Obviously,
Frances fixing up the house
is some kind of metaphor
for fixing up your life.
It was important to me
that we not make
a home-decorating movie, though.
I really was less interested
in the remodeling aspects of the story
than in anything else, and wanted
to spend very little time on it,
and Steve and l agreed that she
would never really decorate her house.
What we mostly did to indicate
an evolution on the set
was to change the way the rooms
were lit as time went on.
Here in the scene when she first
comes, the curtains are half closed
and you can't see the room
all that well,
or have a real sense of the house yet,
and as the story progresses and she
becomes more at home in Italy,
we started to illuminate the rooms
more brightly and with more warmth.
Why? It didn't get more valuable
in the last five minutes.
The contessa feels
that she has asked too little,
since you have agreed to buy it.
That logic is absurd!
Excuse me?
What is the price?
Are you bidding against us?
Wait. We accept the new price.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
WELLS: When l took on
the subject matter of this film,
I was aware of the
not altogether positive opinion
that many Europeans
have of Americans.
And it was important to me
to represent that reality in the film,
which is why I wrote these lines.
You greedy Americans.
You think you are so entitled.
-You ruin everything.
-A lot of us feel really badly about that.
(SPEAKING GERMAN)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
Is it really double the price?
-Il prezzo e veramente il doppio?
-Si.
I can't pay double the price.
But please tell the contessa that...
Up until this point we haven't
really seen Vince Riotta's face,
and this is the first time
we get a really good look at him.
I wanted to get closer to him
as the scene progressed.
The shots were getting tighter
from the first exchanges
in the earlier part of the scene.
...men,
chocolate.
WELLS: l like the way he watches her
in the scene.
And when we first meet his character
and he is the real estate agent,
I think the audience might dismiss him,
not understanding
that he is about to be
one of the most important characters
in the movie.
But right here,
when you see the look in his eyes
after she makes her admission,
it's a very powerful thing.
We know that he sees her and that
he knows that she has a story.
CONTESSA: No.
No.
I'm sorry, signora. The contessa's
family have lived here for generations,
so understandably
it is very difficult for her to sell.
Money is not the only issue.
She needs...
Un segno di Dio. Un segno.
A sign. I understand.
I believe in signs, too.
Well, thank you. Thank you.
Prego.
WELLS: So this special effect
is accomplished by
an Italian grip standing on a ladder
with a broomstick that has a spoon
attached to the end of it
in which is some yogurt
mixed with poppy seeds.
It was important that the guy
with the best aim take the shot,
so we wouldn't have to
wash Diane's hair and reset.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
WOMAN: First we open an account
for you. Then you transfer the money.
Here is the legal description of the land,
two oxen, two days.
-I'm sorry?
-It's old-fashioned.
The legal description.
The land is measured by how long
it would take two oxen to plow it.
That makes sense.
WELLS: This actress here is Claudia
Gerini, and she is very famous in ltaly.
She is always on television,
doing movies, hosting award shows.
She is everywhere.
And it was hard work for us to find
a day that she could spare the time
and come do this scene with us.
But I wanted CIaudia,
because she is so sexy and beautiful,
and represents the kind of Italian style
that I saw everywhere.
Women who kind of lead
with their sexuality and power,
Claudia has a lot of that.
-Normale?
-Normale.
Normale.
FRANCES: l have bought a house
in a foreign country.
A house and the land
it takes two oxen two days to plow.
Not having a plow or an ox,
I'll have to take their word on that.
Buyer's remorse is a very common
affliction among new homeowners.
WELLS: Something that doesn't
take place in Frances' book,
but I thought was important
in the movie,
was the sense of absolute terror
and regret
about buying a 300-year-old house
in a foreign country,
when you are all by yourself.
FRANCES: l have inherited
10,000 empty wine bottles,
one grape...
WELLS: By far the hardest thing that
we got on film was the scorpion.
Scorpions, like sheep,
are not very fond of taking direction.
We spent way too much time
watching scorpions crawl around.
The scorpions were in Frances' book,
but, unfortunately,
they were also in the house
that I was living in with my family
while we were shooting.
It became the norm to hear something
crunch under your foot
in the middle of the night when
you were on your way to the bathroom.
When l created Frances' character,
I had it in my mind
that she was motherless.
Which in most myths and fairy tales
is actually a precondition
of becoming a heroine.
To me this meant that she was ripe
for a meaningful encounter
with the Madonna,
the most powerful mother figure
of them all.
PATTI: You did what?
Frances bought a house in Tuscany!
And you're gonna live there? Alone?
WELLS: Patti's apartment is a set
that we built on the lot at Cinecitta.
It turned out to be challenging
getting an American look in Italy.
And we hired an American set dresser,
Nick Evans,
to bring props from the United States.
He went shopping at Target
and brought 600 pounds of props
with him through customs.
Well, I don't know.
You're the one who made the
"empty-shell person
standing at the crossroads" speech.
Oh, yeah, that was me.
Okay. Wow!
So you bought a villa in Tuscany.
-What's the place like?
-It needs a little work.
Well, who's gonna do it?
-I am.
-You are?
-I never realized you were so handy.
-I can do things, you know.
-Remember I fixed that drain.
-In your kitchen? No, that was me.
I handed you the rubber thingy.
The plunger? That was Tom.
I can't believe it.
Why, why did you just say his name?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, I forgot. I'm sorry.
-I can make this work. You know?
-(RUMBLE OF THUNDER)
Of course I didn't mean I was gonna
do all the work myself. I'm in Italy.
I can hire the muscular descendants
of Roman gods...
WELLS: l love Diane Lane
and Sandra Oh together.
They had great chemistry
and managed to project
a sense of history onto their friendship.
I also love the way
they looked together physically.
I think they were
exceptionally well matched.
And not surprisingly, they remained
friends after the show.
They always had fun on set together,
and it made it easy for them
to come up with wonderful improvs
like this bit that Sandra added here.
-Can you star-69 Italy?
-No.
I'm gonna try.
Hello?
Okay.
WELLS: This is the first day of shooting
here, and in some ways it was difficult,
because we had effects,
we had wind, we had rain.
We were actually
shooting during the day,
which meant
that the location was tented.
But it was good for Diane
to have something really active
to do on day one.
It's always hard to break the ice,
and the physical demands of this scene
helped Diane lose the inhibitions
of the first day.
Diane really had to trust me
that I was going to put some
scary lightning out those windows,
because she was making the face of
someone who was completely terrified.
This washing machine here,
it's being moved along
by somebody pulling a string.
And then, there is an air gun
in a hole underneath it
that makes itjump up into the air.
We shot it with two cameras
running at two different speeds.
And, boy,
that was really exciting for me.
Two cameras, you know.
Michael Bay, watch out.
This owl was much better
at taking direction
than the sheep or the scorpions.
I think he has got a great spirit.
And I like the way Diane
connects to other solitary animals.
There was some kind of
method to my madness here.
I feel like animals have a lot of pathos.
And, obviously,
their greatest interest is in surviving.
And Frances' survival instinct
needs to kick in
at this time of her life also.
And I felt that she had a kinship,
a relationship to all the solitary animals
that show up in the movie.
Vince Riotta, who plays Signor Martini,
he was not a very well-known actor
when I was introduced to him
by Beatrice Kruger,
my Italian casting director.
And in some ways, I think,
the thing that scared me the most
on this movie was casting Vince.
Because I didn't see
any other film on him.
I only had his auditions to go on.
And they were so perfectly pitched,
that I felt that I had to go with him.
As a man, Vince is a young,
kind of boyish guy
with a lot of youthful energy,
and the restrained, reserved,
wizened man
that he plays in this movie
is entirely a performance
that he created.
Oh, wonderful.
You should have been an architect.
You have excellent taste.
So, do you think it can be done?
Heating pipes, a week.
The bathrooms, three days.
Signora, give me the keys of this place
and in one month I will give you back
the keys to your palace.
Just...
Just leave it to me.
WELLS: ln this montage
with all the contractors
I think about my casting directors
and how important they were to me.
A director can only choose actors
from amongst the group
that the casting director brings.
And those two were so creative
and had such a good sense
of the script
that I owe them a lot for finding
me actors like the ones that I did.
This is Massimo Sarchielli right here
who'd been in a lot of Fellini's movies.
I was thrilled to have an alumnus
of La Strada in my movie.
Really? Oh.
You wanna see the rest of the house?
Okay. Yes, yes.
WELLS: Finding the three actors
who would play the Polish contractors
was one of the biggest casting
challenges of the film.
And finding a young,
beautifully fresh-faced actor
who could speak Polish and handle
physically demanding scenes
was especially difficult.
Finding Pawel Szajda was like
finding a needle in a haystack.
He is an American, actually,
born to Polish immigrant parents.
And he sent us an audition tape
that he made all alone.
He turned the camera on
and ran in front of it
pretending to listen
to off-camera voices.
It slayed me. This is his first film.
-I am Pawel.
-Pawel. Nice to meet you.
WELLS: That's Valentine Pelka.
He is British.
And Sasa Vulicevic filled out
the third role.
He is a Croatian living in Rome.
-Zbignew.
Frances.
What do you think of Nino?
I know his mother.
If he does a bad job, it's...
Well, then...
-Okay, yes.
-Okay, yes?
Yes. Yes.
Okay. Yes.
WELLS: l tried to cast my Polish guys
from Poland.
But the Italians were being slow
about approving work permits
for Polish people to come
and work in Italy,
which seemed very ironic to me,
because, in a sense,
the Polish characters
represent the plight of the immigrant
worker anywhere in the world.
And here we were having
so many problems
bringing people from Poland into Italy,
and so many problems
getting work permits
that I was forced to cast them
from other parts of the world.
When l look at this scene,
I remember all the plaster dust that all
the actors had to swallow that day.
And considering that it was the first
working day for the Polish guys,
(LAUGHING) l think they all considered
quitting after one day of work.
The fact that I didn't have real
Polish actors to play the Polish workers
meant that later on in post-production
I had to add in some dialogue in Polish
once we'd had time
to have Polish-speaking people
teach us some words.
And in Los Angeles one day a guy
came to fix my stove that had broken,
and I started talking to him
and it turned out he was Polish.
I asked him if he could
come into the studio
and record some
temporary dialogue for us, and he did.
l think he's got his SAG card now.
No more ovens for him.
FRANCES: "Kurwa mac" means
"holy shit" in Polish.
I learned that that day.
The fact that I'm trying
to speak Polish in Italy
is just one of the many surprises
around here.
Is he a licensed electrician?
WELLS: Valentine Pelka's
character, Jerzy,
had the most mystery
of all the Polish workers.
And in keeping with my idea
that I would give everyone in the movie
a broken heart,
I had decided that Jerzy
should wear a wedding ring,
meaning he had had
to leave his beloved in Poland.
Valentine is also married,
and he was missing his wife and child
who were back home in England,
and the concept worked for him.
FRANCES: Every day l watch
for the old man with the flowers.
WELLS: We called this character
"the old man with the flowers."
FRANCES: Did he love someone here?
WELLS: And one of my ltalian
colleagues on the movie
suggested that we approach
Mario Monicelli
to see if he would play the part.
This was like getting
John Huston to act in your movie.
Mario Monicelli is one of the most
famous directors in Italy alive today,
and he's made over 60 films.
He is an icon.
Having him in the movie
was a great honor.
He was very nice to me that day.
Only wanting to serve me
as best he could as an actor.
He was enormously polite.
FRANCES: Fortunately, there are some
things here you just can't do alone.
It's my neighbor Placido
who's teaching me about olives.
WELLS: When I look at these olives
I remember how much fear we had
that by the time we would shoot
the olive grove,
all the olives would be off the trees.
We kept delaying and delaying
and delaying shooting this scene
because of the bad weather.
Every time it was scheduled
there would be a downpour that day,
and we'd end up shooting
something in the house instead.
The day that we finally went out there,
there was no possibility
to postpone the shoot one more day,
and so we went out there even
though it had rained in the morning,
and, thank God, the rain stayed
in the clouds enough hours
for us to get the scene.
That actress is Giulia Steigerwalt,
and I felt that she was
the perfect counterpart to Pawel.
They are both very young actors.
They were both 20 years old
when we shot the movie.
They had some
genuine innocence to them.
I don't really know how they'd feel
about my saying that,
but there was something true
in each of them
that made them perfect
to play the parts.
They ended up
becoming extremely good friends.
Francesca, are you busy tonight?
No.
Then come to dinner.
It's unhealthy to eat alone.
WELLS: When that actor did that,
we all laughed so hard we hit the floor.
His name is Marco Bonini
and he is a very popular actor in Italy.
(SOBBING)
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
-Is she okay?
-Of course. She's fine.
WELLS: The grandmotherhere
is EveIina Gori,
and I was thrilled to work with her.
She was already in her 90s
when she agreed to take this part,
and she'd been an actress all of her life
and loved being in front of the camera.
She had her own way of doing things.
She couldn't exactly
do lines as written,
but she had such a significant
presence because of her age, I think,
that I decided to rewrite the scenes
so that she could be in them
even though she had limited
physical ability at the time.
No.
-Do you have one?
-One? Hah!
(BEGINS SOBBING)
I knew this would happen. Remember?
Don't blame me.
I told him not to get her that computer.
She got an email lover.
You see? From Ecuador!
Finally, she had to tell him her age,
and now...
WELLS: Evelina didn't speak
any English,
and I didn't speak Italian,
the bane of my existence.
So we were always talking
to each other through interpreters.
And I don't know
that she really ever knew
what the movie was about, or read
the whole script or anything like that,
but she knew that it was her part
to care about love and defend love,
and she felt very passionate
on that topic.
So what you see from Evelina
comes from deep inside her.
Come si dice in inglese? Celibe?
Celibe...
Celibate? Celibate?
No. I mean...
Well, actually, I have to admit
it has been a while.
Celibe in Italian means single.
He's not asking when you last had sex,
he's asking whether
or not you're married.
Thank you.
WELLS: l love Diane's
vulnerability here.
I always find, as a screenwriter,
that it's important
to kick around your protagonist
and drag them through the mud
as much as possible.
I'm always looking for ways
to beat up my characters.
Oh, my God.
FRANCES: I feel like such an idiot.
Don't. Flirting's a ritual in Italy.
Just enjoy it.
Taste this. It's gorgeous.
Mm.
-How do you do it?
-Do what?
This.
WELLS: This character Katherine
is quite obviously in the spirit
of Fellini's women.
The costume designer, Nicoletta,
dressed her in replica costumes
from some of Fellini's films.
And this fantastic hat ended up flying
into the fountain the night that we shot.
As you can see, it's very windy
and it wasn't pinned
onto her head well enough.
I will never forget how when
the hat flew off into the fountain
that Nicoletta dove into the fountain
at 3:00 in the morning
on a freezing night to fish it out of there.
And then,
there was some touch and go time
with the blow dryer in the cafe
that you see in the background,
while we hoped that the hat
could be restored to its former glory
and could still make it
through the scene.
He wasn't just a great director,
he gave great advice.
I'm listening.
Fefe said you have to live spherically,
in many directions.
WELLS: Katherine does espouse
Fellini's philosophies.
The things that she says
are actual quotes from Fellini.
And I felt that they had thematic value
for the movie.
FRANCES: So now l was getting
posthumous advice from Il Maestro.
And I tried to follow it by pulling ivy
spherically
and with childish enthusiasm.
WELLS: A lot ofpeople
are terrified of snakes.
I am not one of them
and neither is Diane.
She was perfectly happy
to help us get this shot
and grab the snake and try and
direct its head back over the window.
Niente qui.
Niente. Not here.
WELLS: This scene we always
referred to as the train scene.
I always thought of it
as the center of the movie.
(GASPS)
No, it's a joke.
WELLS: We all looked forward
to the shooting of this scene.
We rehearsed it mostly in blocking.
I brought Vince and Diane
up to the room one day during lunch,
and we kind of walked
through the paces of it.
We had spent a day,
the three of us, previously,
reading over the scenes
of the entire movie.
That was all the time we ever spent
rehearsing was that one day.
Diane had one day with each actor.
I'm sorry.
WELLS: But poor Vince had so
anticipated shooting this scene
and had had to do it for me
so many times in auditions
that by the time we finally shot it,
he must've,
oh, l don't know,
done it 20 times already.
It was important to me
that the character of Frances
talk about her divorce again
in this scene.
We hadn't really heard about it
for a long time.
Not since her character
left San Francisco.
And I thought maybe we felt
that it was behind her.
I like the way it comes up here
right out of the blue
to show that this is still something
that she is really grappling with
and that she is identifying herself by.
You shouldn't have to wake up
day after day after something like that,
trying to understand
how in the world you didn't know.
WELLS: Stephen McCabe brought
that little fireplace in for me.
l wanted to give Signor Martini
something to do.
A way to hide from her
while she is telling him
all these terribly personal things.
I felt that his character would be
both embarrassed by the intimacy,
and also kind of thrilled by it.
And it was nice for Vince
to be able to stay busy with something
while he got through the scene.
The fireplace works for the scene,
but when I see it I am reminded
of how poorly it actually functioned,
spewing smoke into the room that
choked the actors every 45 seconds.
Suffice to say,
that's not how it's supposed to work.
We had to stop constantly
to air out the room,
which was hard for them to do
in an emotional scene like this one.
Why did you do it, then?
WELLS: The story that Signor Martini
tells Frances in this scene
about the train tracks built
across the Semmering Pass
is a true story related to me
by my Austrian father.
And if I'd never heard that story,
I don't know if I would've
ever written this movie.
It was the springboard and, actually,
the reason for the film.
Between Austria and Italy
there is a section of the Alps
called the Semmering.
It is an impossibly steep,
very high part of the mountains.
They built a train track over these Alps
to connect Vienna and Venice.
They built these tracks
even before there was a train in
existence that could make the trip.
They built it because they knew
someday the train would come.
WELLS: I love the transition
on Diane's face right here
when she goes from just being touched
that he told her the story
into thinking
that maybe she needs him.
And I love the way
he registers that look.
They had fantastic
unspoken communication.
I think your snake
has gone for the evening.
Yes, I think you're right.
WELLS: There is a lot of
beautiful tension
between these two in this scene,
and one of my favorite things
that we were able to do in the movie
is show that sometimes men
and women can be friends
without crossing any taboo lines
and staying true
to their other commitments,
despite some great attraction
that they might have for each other.
I liked being able to portray
that kind of friendship in this movie.
Buona notte, signora.
Buona notte, Signor Martini.
E grazie per tutto.
Prego.
(SIGHS)
FRANCES: A train track through
the Alps before there was a train.
Signor Martini wants me to have faith,
something I've never been good at...
WELLS: This image is called
the Running Madonna.
When I reached Italy,
my assistant Edoardo Petti,
who later became
an associate producer on the movie,
he told me about this tradition
that existed elsewhere in Italy,
not in Tuscany,
but we borrowed it for the film.
I included this painting
by Piero della Francesca,
because he is native of Tuscany,
and because
that image of the Madonna
protecting even the sinners I thought
would be important to Frances.
FRANCES: Aunt Mary is
everywhere here,
her calm presence assuring us
that all things will go on
as they have before.
WELLS: This Christmas scene
made me feel like a real movie director.
We had snow. We had extras.
We had a manger.
You know,
what more could you ask for?
Just about everybody in this scene
is recognizable to me,
because Cortona
was such a small town
and everybody who lived there
wanted to be an extra in the movie,
and so the people that you see
crossing back and forth here
were also really the people
working in the cafes
and at the hair salon
and in the grocery stores.
Bellissima.
What a beautiful family. Wow.
WELLS: When l watch this scene
I am reminded that we had
a lot of snow issues that night.
We had a very noisy snow machine
for covering the entire piazza.
And I had asked that we find a way
to have snow fall on actors quietly
when we were in their close-ups,
but this quiet way
never exactly materialized,
and the machines that we did have
would've drowned out their dialogue,
and I would've had to replace it all later.
So, instead, l settled on having guys
off-camera throw snow into the air
and fan it in the actors' direction.
This was quieter, but as you can see,
it was also, shall we say, inconsistent.
There are so many compromises
that you make along the way.
-Merry Christmas, Signora Mayes.
-Buon Natale.
WELLS: Frances Mayes, in her book,
talks a lot about food.
It's a very important element
of Italian life.
And Frances, as a poet,
writes about it in such a way
that food takes on a lot
of other kinds of significance.
And I had decided early on
that I wasn't going to try and make
a great movie about cooking.
There are some fantastic movies
about cooking,
like Eat Drink Man Woman
or Like Water for Chocolate.
Those are movies
that made it very clear to me
that I wasn't going to try and do that.
I had too much story to tell
to center the movie around food.
It wasn't the way I'd structured the film.
And I thought that a little
would go a long way.
So this is pretty much the only time
you see a lot of cooking
going on in the movie.
I like the fact that she feeds
her immediate family,
the guys that she sees every day.
And the food that you see here
was prepared by Antonella
from Tonino's Restaurant,
it's a place that we loved to eat
and where they were very,
very nice to us during the shoot.
We would always go there
on Friday nights.
And they would bring out dish
after dish after dish,
each one more delicious than the last,
and for me,
I took a lot of pleasure out of it,
because I was really working
such long hours
going to the dailies after shooting,
and we were shooting six-day weeks,
and when we went to Tonino's
every now and then and had a meal,
that was a real moment of relaxation
for us all.
Bravo!
Bravo! Bravo!
Riusciro, riuscirai, riuscira, riusciremo,
riuscirete, riusciranno.
-Good.
-See, Frances? Italian is easy.
WELLS: It's true that I co-authored
the screenplay
for George of the Jungle,
but this is not an homage to moi.
I knew that I wanted to stick
an American movie out there,
and since my film was
for the Walt Disney Company,
I chose a film from their library
to make life simple.
And itjust seemed funny to me
to have Pawel say outside,
"See, Frances, ltalian is easy."
And then to see that even George
of the Jungle could speak Italian.
Have you talked to her yet?
Si. I have talked to her.
Why don't you go sit next to her? Go on.
Okay.
WELLS: This scene is shot inside
the Teatro Signorelli in Cortona.
A beautiful movie theater
where this movie
will probably play someday soon.
Katherine?
WELLS: l love the exterior
of this building.
These are the rewards
of shooting on location.
If you tried to recreate that somewhere,
you would never come up with
something as fantastic as that facade.
This set we dressed with furniture,
but the walls are original
from Napoleon's era.
As a matter of fact, Napoleon
actually slept in this room, so they said.
-I think I'll come back another time.
-Why? You don't bother me.
Frances, this is Zeus.
WELLS: Ah, Zeus.
Zeus in the digital underwear.
Stare closely at the buttocks
and you will see
that they move separately
from the fabric that is covering them.
Although the CGl guys
did a very good job.
You see, what happened here
is that I was contractually obligated
to deliver a PG-13 movie.
And originally that actor
came out with a nude butt.
And I received an R rating for the film,
even though
actually the scene is very innocent.
So in order to roII that back to PG-13,
we decided to put some underwear
on Zeus' bum.
And to that end, there are gentlemen
at a certain visual effects house
in Los Angeles
who worked many, many long hours
staring at the musculature
of his behind trying to figure out
how to make those digital underpants
move accordingly.
I just got here. I just walked in the door.
How are you ever going to be happy
if you keep wallowing?
WELLS: ln this scene, Lindsay talks
about her ladybug philosophy.
This was actually something
that came to me
through being the mother
of a two-and-a-half-year-old
who is always on the lookout
for ladybugs.
So?
So, go work on your house
and forget about it.
I said go!
I'm going!
WELLS: At this point in the film,
I felt like
we all wanted to get going somewhere
other than Cortona.
I figured that the character
was probably starting to feel
claustrophobic in that environment,
and stuck with the Polish guys
that were driving her a little bit crazy
since she was seeing them all the time.
FRANCES: There comes a time
when you no longer want
shaky guys staring at you,
thinking God knows what,
whispering things in Polish
you're really, really glad
you don't understand.
"Kocham ciebie," "Nie rozumiem..."
I mean, there's only so much of that
you can take
before there comes a time
when you reallyjust have to get out.
WELLS: We moved to Rome
and shot there for about seven days.
This is the Vittoriano.
And I actually saw it
out the window of my apartment
that we rented in Rome.
It was exciting to be shooting
in the center
of this fantastically beautiful city.
We chose a street for this scene
that's known for its antique shops.
Traditionally, people work
outside their shops
refurbishing furniture,
which is what we depicted here.
-Mamma mia!
-Signorina.
Great.
Hilarious.
Bye.
WELLS: Any woman
who's ever been alone in Italy
understands what this scene is about.
You are American, eh?
-English?
-Irish?
There you are.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
WELLS: When l wanted
to cast Marcello,
it wasn't important to me
that I cast a great-looking actor.
I did not set out to find somebody
as handsome as Raoul obviously is.
But I was very concerned
about finding somebody
who could hold his own
opposite Diane Lane,
and who was really Italian
and who could really speak English
well enough to play the scenes.
Raoul is a superstar in Italy.
There were times when we would
walk down the street together
and we hadn't gone five blocks
before we had attracted a crowd
of 200 people.
But you would never know that
by working with him,
because he is a tremendously modest,
gentlemanly person.
-You are too late.
-I'm sorry?
I have already found somebody else.
My loss.
WELLS: Raoul and Diane
liked each other a lot.
And it was always fun
having the two of them together.
They had a good rapport.
And I especially liked the way
Raoul had a charming
and kind of trustworthy presence.
He didn't seem like the typical
Latin lover, wolf-whistling,
sleaze ball kind of guy.
I felt that I understood
why Diane's character
would be attracted to him
and willing to jump in his car
afterjust having met him.
-Is it far?
-About three hours.
-Two, if I drive fast.
-Two hours?
WELLS: When Frances meets MarceIIo,
it's clearly something
the audience has been waiting for.
Ever since Patti said,
"Have you met him yet,
"the man you're going to meet,"
we've been on the lookout
for this romantic interlude in her life.
And I felt like it's also part and parcel
with stories about people on the road.
It's the kind of time
when you are open to things,
and you have adventures
and you let yourself talk to strangers.
And I like the adventurous aspect of it.
But more than that,
this was an opportunity for me
to show her coming back to life
and taking chances.
You're willing.
WELLS: There are expectations built up
between the two of them
in these scenes that are paid off
in an unconventional manner
later on in the movie.
It was a chance to sort of
play with some stereotypes
and make fun of them at the same time.
The comedy was very important
in order to accomplish that.
Yellow light, decoration.
-And what about red lights?
-Just a suggestion.
(LAUGHS)
WELLS: And now we are in
southern Italy
on the Amalfi Coast and that's Positano.
And this is one of the most famous
stretches of road in the world.
This piece of music
is one of the first things
that Chris wrote for the movie.
And he didn't write it
for any scene in particular.
And it was so romantic,
I wanted to find a place for it,
but wasn't sure that I would.
Then we realized
that it suited this drive very nicely.
Once again, we hadn't made the
proper sacrifices to the weather gods,
because we were absolutely dogged
by rain when we were in Positano.
You are barely seeing
any complete takes here,
because we always had to stop
when it would suddenly begin raining
and we'd start over again.
It's miraculous that this sequence
comes off as looking somewhat sunny
when, in fact, we were getting
rained out every 10 minutes.
This is your bar.
We are a family. I work here.
And I sleep there...
WELLS: During rehearsal week,
there was a day
that Raoul and I spent together.
And we had some lunch
and then, afterwards,
he poured me a glass of limoncello,
the liqueur made from lemons
that come from the south of Italy.
And he told me
that he knew how to make it.
And I asked him
to explain that process to me.
And as he did, l realized that
I was looking
at a rather intoxicating person
who was in the middle
of a pretty sensuous description
of how these things are made.
And I thought it was funny, actually,
and that it really
needed to go in the movie.
That it could be something
that he could do with Frances
that could unsettle her
and make her smile.
So I told Raoul
that when we got to Positano,
I would ask him to tell Frances
how limoncello was made,
but that I would never write the scene
and he should
never rehearse the scene,
that he should just let it go
from his mind and do it on the day.
I love the way it turned out.
I think Diane helped a little bit
with nudging him with her foot
under the table.
(SPEAKING ITALIAN)
My nephew.
Yes.
WELLS: The Amalfi Coast is usually
absolutely packed with tourists,
but it becomes deserted
in late November,
which is when we were there.
But I love the way
the umbrellas looked on the beach,
and I put them back out there
for the scene.
This scene is very playful
and it's also quite absurd,
but it's an absurdity
that I recognize from life.
There's a certain giddiness
that exists between people
who know something's
about to happen.
And the anticipation is killing them
in this scene.
I like their awkward goofiness.
And I am also guilty of liking a man
who is nice to kittens.
I had the love interest
do the same thing
in a movie I wrote called
The Truth About Cats & Dogs.
Ben Chaplin pets a cat
and Janeane Garofalo falls in love.
l, of course, have never
personally experienced
anything remotely like that.
I run into you in the street in Rome
and... And now we're here and...
Didn't you have some plans today?
Didn't you have something
you had to do?
So what?
If you smash into something good,
you should hold on
until it's time to let go.
WELLS: Raoul spoke English
pretty well,
but he did make
the kind of idiomatic mistakes
that I put into the script.
But he frequently furnished his own,
which I loved.
I like Diane's nervousness
in this scene.
She clearly is on edge.
Her character feeling that
this is reallyjust too much to take.
And I like the way that she laughs
at his ridiculous line.
What?
WELLS: To me,
this kind of back and forth
is part and parcel
with international relationships
and the kinds of misunderstandings
and preconceptions
that we have about each other.
Thank you.
Marcello, I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry. I...
I'm really nervous, you know?
I was married for a long time,
and since then
there hasn't been anybody.
WELLS: All this hyper-romantic stuff
that's going on here,
it's something I thought
was important to do,
so that Frances could be
mistaken in believing for a while
that some kind of fairy-tale ending
could happen to her.
It's all part of this
kind of extended cruelty
that I'm inflicting on her
as part of the journey that she's on.
Yeah.
WELLS: lt's kind of like Lucy holding
the football for Charlie Brown to kick.
It always gets pulled away.
But right now she is in the thrall of it.
I didn't use a lot of magic realism
in the film,
but so many of the naturally available
shots in Italy,
like the fields of sunflowers,
for example,
were so extreme
that they allowed me
to dabble in effects shots
without sacrificing tone.
I really only used them
when they had storytelling value.
Like here, where l used it
to show passage of time.
It made the transition from the beach
to the tabletop feel less abrupt.
-Francesca.
-Yes?
I'm going to make love all over you.
Okay.
WELLS: This love scene
between Diane and Raoul
was shot on the first day
that they worked together.
And, of course,
it wasn't planned that way,
but this was the only scene
that we had to shoot inside
when we were in Positano.
And it was scheduled to be
at the end of the five days
that we spent in that town.
But, of course, it rained on day one,
and this interior was our cover set,
the place that we could film that day
since it was pouring rain outside.
So they ended up
having to do this scene first.
This is when I really admire actors.
(LAUGHING) lt must be so hard.
Imagine eight of us just a few inches
away from them, staring intently.
And they don't even know each other,
and Raoul is married and has two kids,
and Diane is in love
with somebody else,
and here they are, acting.
At least, for the next five minutes.
Okay. Okay.
WELLS: I admire them, because I think
it takes a lot of concentration
to get through a scene like this
naturally and with focus,
when just a few feet away,
there are a bunch of crew members
who are searching their pockets
for a mint or trying not to sneeze.
You have to promise to come back here.
Promise me.
When?
Can you come this weekend?
Well, I think so.
-You think so?
-Mm.
You think so?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
WELLS: This was a fun scene to shoot.
We didn't rehearse it.
We just blocked it.
Diane clearly knew
what the scene was about.
I've still got it. I've still got it.
I've still got it!
Thank God!
Oh, yeah.
WELLS: Nicoletta and I
decided that Katherine
should be having lunch with nuns.
And since she is concerned
about always dressing appropriately
for the occasion,
she would be
in her quasi nun outfit herself.
I love the whipped cream
on that one nun's lip.
Tomorrow.
WELLS: This is a moment that I like
very much in the movie
when Diane is walking
out of the house happy,
her thoughts about Marcello.
She is on her way to Positano.
And then, we see her stop
and a look comes over her.
And we are not at all clear
on who she sees.
And it's a wonderful surprise
that it's Patti.
-Look at you!
-God damn it, Frances.
Hi.
-What?
-I gotta go pee!
WELLS: Sandra works hard on her
characters. She really likes to prepare.
And I remember she told me
that once Nicoletta had given her
this pregnancy pillow,
she wore it around for weeks
in Los Angeles
before she flew out to Italy.
And wore the belly on the airplane
where she was treated with deference
and respect by all.
I think she exploited it a little bit.
Oh, jeez...
So, what's it like
having one of these in Cortona?
I hear the town midwife's pretty good.
She puts a knife under the bed.
To cut the pain.
Florence is an hour away.
You're gonna be delivering this baby
in a hospital gown designed by Armani.
(PATTI CHUCKLES)
WELLS: Sandra did about three
takes of this. This is the second one.
I never found it necessary
with any actor on this movie
to do a lot of takes.
Every one of them was the kind of actor
that is ready to go on take one
and gives you something
that you can use.
I could've cut this entire movie
with the first take of every scene.
Oh, Jesus, Frances!
How do you do it?
How do you ever breathe again?
Pretty soon.
God, I missed you.
WELLS: l shot this phallic tree,
because I thought it represented
what was missing
in the lives of these women.
Don't worry, I'm just kidding.
(CHUCKLING) The importance
and depth of female friendship
is obviously a great big part
of this movie.
And Diane and Sandra
captured it beautifully.
I especially like their performance
in this scene.
I think it's very tender.
There's something strange
about these trees. It's like they know.
And they know
that we know that they know.
They're creepy. Creepy Italian trees.
The baby's gonna like them 'cause
he's gonna be a creepy Italian baby
who goes around saying,
"Ciao, Mamma, "
and doing that backward
hand-wave thing.
Life is strange.
-Where were you going when I arrived?
-Nowhere important.
What's he like?
He's a creepy Italian.
-So go see him.
-I will.
I wanna spend time
with my creepy American friend.
I refuse to screw up your love life.
Don't be ridiculous, Patti.
You are my love life.
WELLS: Ah! The goat.
We shot him in pre-production.
It's a very nice-looking goat.
It was very clean.
We had to dirty it up a little bit,
because the goat owner
had given her a shampoo
before she arrived.
This is the third time in the movie
that Frances notices the spigot.
The first time was on the first day
that she entered the house
and she walked into it
and gave herself a bruise.
And the second time was
after she purchased the house
and she realized
that even if she turns the knob,
she couldn't get any water out of it.
And here in this scene, it's the first time
that she notices that it's dripping.
There's hot water in the toilet bowl.
Oh, my God. That's close to boiling.
They must've
crossed a pipe somewhere.
WELLS: Certain jokes keep me
laughing an abnormally long time.
And this is one of them.
Unless you wanna
give your ass a facial.
That's a contradiction in terms.
I guess it'd be more of an ass-cial.
(SUPPRESSED GIGGLING
NEXT DOOR)
WELLS: So Frances finds
the young lovers in her bed.
And this begins a section of the film
that I always thought of
as a kind of farce.
The same kind of farce that I studied
when I was in high school,
like Beaumarchais' plays.
St. Francesca,
patron saint of horny teenagers?
WELLS: There is class conflict.
There is people sneaking around
behind each other's backs.
There is plots going on.
There is the convenient appearance
of the nemesis atjust the right moment.
It's all in the style
of classic French farce.
Diventeremo pazzi l'uno senza l'altro.
Pawel ha detto che
lui commettera qualcosa di terribile!
Ha detto che diventera un assassino!
Ho provato a parlagli ma non vuole
ascoltarmi e non vuole capire...
Assassinate... Did you say assassinate?
Did she say that you were going
to assassinate somebody?
No. She misunderstand.
I didn't say... Amore,
I didn't say assassino.
WELLS: This is one of the many scenes
in the movie
that was kind of unwieldy
on the first cut.
And one of the many scenes
that Andy Marcus, my editor,
whipped into shape.
He and I had a great time together,
because we shared a sense of humor
and we were always
making each other laugh.
And I was always in favor of economy,
and that was a good thing,
because he was always
shoving economy down my throat
in a really nice way.
Because I can do it as good
as any Italian man, that's why.
And her father will see.
PLACIDO: (OUTSIDE)
Francesca? Francesca?
My father!
-Francesca.
-Placido, hi.
My daughter says you are taking her
to the festa in Montepulciano.
This is true?
Just a moment, please.
I told him you are taking me there
so he will stay home.
-I don't want to lie to your father.
-Oh, come on, Frances. Who cares?
PAWEL: Frances...
If I am not with her,
I will die of a broken heart.
You won't die.
WELLS: So here we are
in Montepulciano,
a neighboring town to Cortona.
And here is a depiction
of a flag throwing festival.
These take place all over Tuscany.
This was something
I was completely unaware of
when I was still in the States.
When I arrived in Italy,
six weeks before we started shooting,
I knew that I needed to find
some kind of Italian festival
or some kind of traditional sport
that Pawel could participate in
and prove his manhood through.
And I didn't know
what I was going to use.
There was archery.
There was barrel-rolling,
and then
I heard about the flag throwing.
And we went to watch it
a bunch of times.
And the more l watched it,
the more I had to
come to the conclusion
that it was men in tights waving flags,
and really not much more.
lt was nice to look at,
but it had its challenges.
It was hard to make Pawel
look very much like
a macho stud flag throwing.
But there is a sweetness to it,
and a sweetness to her reaction to it,
and it's so colorful,
I thought we could make it work.
Whoo!
Yay! Bravo!
WELLS: Here once again, we used
the latest special effects technology
to achieve our ends.
Somebody stood on a ladder
and dropped a Styrofoam pole
on Pawel's head.
We had two days to shoot this scene
and three cameras.
And, as always, my ally in this scene
was my director of photography,
Geoffrey Simpson.
-I threw the flag.
-Si, amore.
They're fine.
Let's go.
WELLS: GeoffSimpson wasn't
the only important cameraman
working on the movie for me.
Because the other one
was my husband,
who shot
a lot of the second unit material,
like this landscape shot right here.
Francesca, you see my daughter.
She seems so different.
Really?
-Chiara is not herself.
-Oh.
Maybe... Do you know
what's bothering her?
Placido, I don't know.
Hey, Frances, look.
You can see Bramasole from here.
See?
Thank you.
WELLS: Diane was always game
for whatever was required of her.
She threw herself into things
wholeheartedly.
And that included the physical comedy.
I really had a good time watching her
the day that we shot this scene.
The way she tore off down that hill.
And when it was time
to fall down the muddy embankment,
she did it with such abandon that
we only did a second take for safety,
because the first one was so hilarious.
Arh...
Wait!
Marcello!
WELLS: Sometimes when
l watch a scene in the film,
I still remember
the shooting day vividly.
And when l watch this scene,
I remember that I had a migraine
the day that we shot this.
And that we were
working on a Saturday,
which meant that the crew was only
going to work seven straight hours,
and that then they were going to leave
come hell or high water.
And it was a big scene to get done
and not the only one
that we had scheduled for the day.
And I remember
everybody starting to pack up to leave
while Sandra was still trying
to come up with her performance
for the last beat of this scene
when she admits
that she is already in labor.
When l look at it,
I remember really how mad I was.
(CHUCKLING) But like so many
other days of shooting on the film,
the behind-the-scenes action
didn't really manifest onscreen.
You could've tied him to a chair,
you could've crippled him!
You could've faked labor, at least!
I wouldn't have had to fake it.
WELLS: l remember that even
the night before
we were scheduled to shoot the scene,
we still didn't have a baby
to play Patti's infant
that was of a believable weight.
And I was very nervous
about finding one
that was young enough
and small enough
to be convincing as a newborn.
This baby was born to a couple
in Rome that was on set that day.
And I remember the very quiet
and reverent atmosphere on set
as they stood behind the camera
nervously watching their infant
being passed from actress to actress.
We didn't really
have Florence out the window.
That's a green screen effect.
So Diane wasn't really
about to heave-ho.
The pink ribbons on the door,
that's a tradition in Italy
that I was unaware of
until I started scouting.
It's something that they do
to announce the arrival of a baby.
And I thought it was a nice addition
to the scene.
Okay...
You're so cute, you're so cute!
WELLS: This flower design
on the ground
is part of something called an infiorata,
a festival where people make fantastic
living tapestries on the ground.
And my regret is that
we were so pushed for time that day
that I had to move on
before I got my wide shot.
And I still haven't really let go
of my disappointment over that.
Still, l think that the sequence works.
A baby is born,
the spring flowers bloom,
and the house is coming back to life.
Frances?
We are finished.
WELLS: l think it's very tender,
this scene.
The Polish guys have
become Frances' family,
and their work is done
and it's time for them to leave.
There was a detail
in Frances Mayes' book
in which the Polish workers
wrote the word "Polonia" on a stone
that they placed
near the bottom of her finished wall.
And I found that very touching.
I like the way the different actors
handle a scene.
I like Valentine's reserve
and continued dignity here.
I like the way Pawel smiles and laughs
kind of in counterpoint
to the emotion of the scene.
l had suggested to Sasa
that he might cry in this scene.
And this is what he did with it.
The traditional structure
of romantic comedy, or human comedy
as this film is, is that things reach
their low point at the end of Act 2.
There is always, at least in my writing,
a point at which the comedy
slows down
and the needs of the characters
in their most sincere form take over.
And we worry about Frances here.
Because we see that,
despite all her efforts,
she still feels alone.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
I had always hoped that these boxes
of books would come as a surprise.
That we had forgotten about them
and that to see them now
would have a certain punch to it.
And the blue vase
functions as a hot object,
meaning an object
that carries a lot of emotional value
and symbolism for my main character.
This photograph represents
the only time
that we actually see
Frances' ex-husband.
I thought that creating a moving image
inside the Polaroid
would evoke her visceral memory
of what it was like
when she used to feel loved.
She looks at that photo
and she knows urgently
that she has to move on.
I love what Chris Beck did
with the music here,
creating the anticipation
for the cut to the next scene.
One hour before l got this shot,
that stone pier
was completely underwater.
And every time I see the shot,
I feel incredibly grateful
that Diane wasn't knocked over
by a wave and dragged out to sea.
The fact that Diane
didn't worry about her safety
is one of the reasons that I love her.
She always wanted the shot
as much as I did.
This sequence
on the back of the motorbike
was shot in about 20 frantic minutes
while most of the crew
was packing to leave Positano
when the sun was going down.
Johnny got it on his Steadicam
sitting on the back of a Polaris.
And once again, Diane eschewed
safety and didn't wear a helmet,
so that we could see all that
beautiful hair flowing in the wind.
There were a lot of challenges
getting this scene done.
For one thing, we all thought that
Raoul Bova's fans would show up,
and we were afraid that
we would be surrounded
by a thousand young women
screaming, "Raoul, Raoul."
But, fortunately, they didn't materialize.
But even without the fans,
this was a tough shooting day.
We battled the elements
getting this scene.
The clouds were
moving incredibly fast.
And every take went in and out
of sun every 30 seconds.
Geoff was calling out F-stop changes
while the actors were performing.
And it rained maybe six times
during Diane's coverage.
And PAs kept running out
with umbrellas to shield her.
Plus we were on a tiny road
that was the only road out of Positano.
And when we weren't
stopping for the sun,
we were stopping to let the traffic out.
It was stressful for the actors.
And when we were done shooting,
I was unconvinced
that the scene would ever cut.
And the fact that it works
is due to Geoff's quick reactions,
my editor and the color timer
at Technicolor, Lee Wimer.
I sent her a really good bottle of wine
after this.
Wow, I...
I came at a bad time.
Francesca, wait. Wait. Wait.
I'm sorry you're hurt.
But what did you expect?
What did I expect?
You came to Bramasole.
You left that note.
-I thought... I thought that you...
-Just a minute, just a minute.
Months ago, we had a beautiful affair.
WELLS: The dialogue in this scene
was a little tricky to write.
It's an inherently melodramatic scene,
but there is truth in it, l think,
and that's what saves it.
Of course, Frances' affair
with the fantasy man can't work out.
And if it had, this movie
would've been entirely different,
with a different meaning
and a different tone.
As it is, the scene shows,
l think, a realistic end
to what was essentially
an unrealistic affair.
There was my friend,
and she was going to have a baby...
There were many, many other things.
Important things you had to do.
And you couldn't wait.
WELLS: I didn't want Raoul's character
to end up as the bad guy.
I tried to construct dialogue
that was fair to both characters.
And I think what Marcello is saying
in this scene has integrity.
Raoul felt that his character
was full of sincere regret.
We did about seven takes on Raoul
with the clouds blowing wildly
across the sun,
but each take was
wonderfully nuanced
and sort of heartbreaking.
There is someone for you, Francesca.
Goodbye.
Francesca.
WELLS: This scene, which we just
called "the fountain scene,"
was the one I was most concerned
about pulling off.
Asking an actress to do her impression
ofAnita Ekberg in La Dolce Vita
is a tall order.
It was really pretty risky.
And I knew that we'd be referencing
one of the most famous love scenes
in cinema history. It's not the kind
of thing you want to get wrong.
But Lindsay,
with the costuming help of Nicoletta,
she really pulled it off.
It had been freezing and windy as hell.
But for some reason,
it warmed up that night
and the air was completely still.
And I remember feeling that
that was a good omen.
Is she drunk?
WELLS: We dressed Vince in a
black suit like Marcello Mastroianni.
And I think he and Diane
have perfect comic timing here.
Chris Beck's score also
gives the scene a lot of help.
He composed something
very eerie and beautiful
that was very much related
to the kind of scores
that Nino Rota did for Fellini.
(APPLAUSE AND CHEERING)
Then, of course,
there is the fountain itself,
which l think is Stephen McCabe's
crowning achievement in the film.
There was no fountain
in the Piazza Signorelli in Cortona,
and Steve knew
that I wanted something
in a heroic classical form
like the Trevi Fountain in Rome.
He designed this statue and we built it
from scratch out of fiberglass.
That's the royal "we," of course,
because I personally
didn't get my hands dirty.
When the fountain was first installed,
the town was scandalized to see
that the male figure sported an
anatomically proportionate package,
and it caused such a scandal
that the local paper
accused me of being
a Communist sympathizer,
because the statue hung left.
At which point,
l decided to order a reduction,
which I heard was carried out
under the cover of night.
Do you think I make a good Sylvia?
You were wonderful.
Here.
WELLS: This is the scene that makes
Katherine's character work for me.
Without this scene,
Katherine is an eccentric
who suffers some kind
of narcissistic delusions.
But with this scene,
we realize that Katherine
has made a conscious choice to live
in her flamboyant and grand style.
She is not a marginal,
almost psychotic person
caught in fantasies and delusions,
she is a real woman
who has made decisions
about how she is going to handle pain
in her life.
And how she is going
to incorporate joy.
And here with the monologue
that she has at the end of the scene,
I think we really understand
what makes her tick.
You know who I really love the most
from all the films?
Cabiria.
You remember at the end,
when another man has left her
in the most terrible way,
and she thinks it's all over for her?
Then she sees some children
playing in the street, making music,
and before she knows it,
she's smiling again.
That's what Fefe always said,
"No matter what happens,
"always keep your childish innocence.
"It's the most important thing."
WELLS: When Frances
returns to the house,
we see that the entryway
has remained the same
since the day
that she first arrived at Bramasole.
It signals that the house
is still incomplete,
as is Frances' journey.
I can't... I can't talk about it now.
Fran...
WELLS: I think Frances is almost
frighteningly miserable in this scene.
She's reached her lowest
and most faithless moment.
But that's also when everything
can start turning around for her.
Stupid. Stupid.
WELLS: Once again,
I think we only shot this scene twice.
Diane doesn't need to do something
like this over and over.
The very first time she does it,
she is entirely emotionally prepared.
(SOBBING OUTSIDE)
This is the scene
that almost didn't happen.
It was our very last day of shooting.
And we worked from maybe
4:00 in the afternoon
until 4:00 in the morning.
EveIina Gori,
the grandmother character,
she had had a heart attack
about six weeks earlier
after having shot most of her scenes.
There were people who felt
that she should not return to work,
that she shouldn't be in this scene
and she shouldn't complete the movie.
I felt differently about it.
If Evelina was up for it,
I wanted to fight to keep her
in the scene and not to rewrite it.
I respected her a lot,
she'd been an actress her entire life.
And we both felt that this might be
her last role before she retired.
And I thought it was important
that she complete the movie
for me, of course, and for the film.
But also, out of respect for Evelina.
The fact that she could only
come to work on this particular day,
this last day, conflicted
with Anita Zagaria's schedule,
that's the actress that plays the mother.
And she was working
on another movie that day
and couldn't start until the afternoon.
Diane had been fulfilling commitments
on Unfaithful
in England that weekend and had to
fly back for this last day of shooting.
It was freezing cold and pouring rain.
Everyone was tired.
Tensions were high.
And it was one of the most important
scenes in the movie.
Wait.
Won't you give your blessing?
What if this is it?
The real thing. A love that lasts forever.
-What you describe is only in fairy tales.
-No, it's not.
And how do you know?
From personal experience?
WELLS: When l first wrote this scene
and I realized that by the end of it
Frances was going to claim Pawel
as part of her family,
the themes of the film
really gelled for me.
I thought it was meaningful
that Frances was fighting
for the happiness of others
even in the midst of her misery.
And I thought that
she was creating her salvation,
even though she didn't realize that.
Mamma, Mamma!
He has no family!
That's not true.
He has me.
I am his family.
(CHURCH BELLS RINGING)
WELLS: We looked at a lot of churches
before I decided on this
relatively unadorned medieval one.
This interior, by the way,
is not the interior of the church
that you saw in the exterior shot.
This one had a purity and a symmetry
about it that really appealed to me
more than the baroque churches
that we looked at.
And the piece of music
that you are hearing
was the first thing
that Chris scored for the movie.
He created this piece
months before he started
working on the rest of the film.
And I played it while we were shooting.
It really created the mood
inside the church
and helped the actors
come up with their performances.
Diane said that
with that piece of music,
she really didn't have to do
any work of her own
to come up with her emotion
for the scene.
ll corpo di Cristo.
Amen.
ll sangue di Cristo.
WELLS: l felt a lot ofaffection
for the characters in this movie.
And this is
an admittedly traditional wrap-up
going on at this wedding reception.
We are getting a lot of final glimpses
of characters
that we came to care about.
Visually, we designed
the wedding reception
around white and yellow,
the colors of the lemons and wisteria.
And it feels like
the garden and the house
have finally arrived at their full fruition.
Mamma!
(GUESTS CHANT)
Bacio! Bacio! Bacio! Bacio!
WELLS: There is an undeniable
sweetness to this scene,
particularly when Frances
sees her old friend, Signor Martini.
He looks like a groom standing there
waiting for her to walk down the aisle
to meet him.
What are you thinking?
WELLS: Their friendship is one
of my favorite things in the movie.
It's been earned.
And when he points out
that her wishes have been granted,
there is a sweet melancholy feeling
of arrival to that
that reminds me
of the kind of resolution
you find in an O. Henry story.
Yeah.
And you said you wanted
there to be a family here.
You're right.
I got my wish.
WELLS: l love Diane's performance
as she realizes
that she has, indeed,
gotten everything she's asked for.
She seems stunned
and sort of quietly amazed.
ln the book Under the Tuscan Sun,
Frances Mayes is married to Ed Mayes
and she writes about him
on almost every page of her memoir.
I thought it was important
for my adaptation
that I bring Ed Mayes
into the story somewhere
and here he is,
played by David Sutcliffe.
But in my mind, I didn't think
she necessarily ended up with this guy.
I didn't put her in a wedding dress.
I didn't get her pregnant,
which would've been a denial
of what came before.
I just wanted to show that
once she had achieved a sense
of completion on her own,
and once she realized that she, indeed,
already had everything she needed,
that then she was open
for more good things to come her way.
No, no.
Don't worry. It was by far the very best
bad review I've ever received.
-You're kidding.
-I'm not.
It helped me get to my next book.
Anyway, I've been traveling
around Tuscany.
Someone said that you lived up here,
and...
WELLS: Eversince l became
a screenwriter 15 years ago,
I've been warned and admonished
about too many endings on movies.
And I think that this movie
may have more endings
than any movie
I've ever seen in my life.
But it works for me. It feels like
all the dominoes were lined up.
Now I flick the first one with my finger
and they all start to fall
with satisfying clacks.
FRANCES: They say they built
the train tracks
over the Alps
between Vienna and Venice
before there was a train
that could make the trip.
They built it anyway.
They knew one day
the train would come.
Any arbitrary turning along the way,
and l would be elsewhere,
I would be different.
What are four walls, anyway?
They are what they contain.
The house protects the dreamer.
Unthinkably good things can happen,
even late in the game.
It's such a surprise.
WELLS: There is an inevitability
to what happens in this scene.
But I've always felt that unpredictability
is an overrated virtue in movies.
Especially in romantic comedies
or human comedies like this one,
unpredictability isn't really
part of the genre.
We know we are headed
for a happy ending.
And we want to go there.
Of course, the ending is predictable.
It's not the fact that it happens
that's supposed to be
the source of pleasure.
It's how it happens and how the actors,
how the characters react
and the impact that it has upon them.
(LAUGHING)
The water here is a sort of baptism
as it washes her feet.
The look on her face seems
somehow transcendent.
Someone once told her
that one day she'd be happy again,
and here she realizes
that that person was right.